[Music]
[音乐]
what I have here is a variety of
我这里有各种
different shapes and sizes of poop yeah
形状和大小的便便，这
what does this tell us about our health
说明了什么呢？
well if your poop looks like this to me
如果你的便便长这样，在我看来，那就应该
that's grounds to talk to a doctor Dr
去看医生了。
will gtz world-renowned gut health
威尔·格茨医生是世界知名的肠道健康
Doctor Who has a wealth of information
专家，他拥有丰富的知识，告诉我们
on how we can improve our gut health
如何
through food and lifestyle changes we
通过饮食和生活方式的改变来改善肠道健康。我们
are currently living through an epidemic
目前正经历着
of gut health issues and if we want to
肠道健康问题的流行，如果我们想
be healthy humans we absolutely need a
成为健康的人，就绝对需要一个
healthy gut microbiome in order to
健康的肠道微生物群。
accomplish that so let's break this down
所以，让我们来分析一下。
first of all microbes are visible on
首先，微生物在
your thumb there are as many microbes as
你的拇指上就能看到。
there are people in the UK really and
事实上，英国的微生物数量和人口数量一样多。
gut microbes play a critical and
肠道微生物
essential role in controlling whether or
在控制
not you suffer from depression because
你是否患有抑郁症方面起着至关重要的作用，因为
95% of the happy hormone is produced by
95%的快乐激素是由
the gut it controls your cognition your
肠道产生的。它控制着你的认知、
memory your energy levels your gut is
记忆和能量水平。你的肠道是
the place where you are making decisions
你做决定的地方。一项又一项的
and study after study after study shows
研究表明，
us that when people eat more not only do
当人们吃得更多时，
they empower the gut microbes but also
他们不仅会增强肠道微生物的活性，还会
they lose weight they're less likely to
减轻体重，降低
die of heart disease less likely to be
死于心脏病的可能性，降低被
diagnosed with multiple different types
诊断出多种疾病的可能性。
of cancer no way yes what about alcohol
癌症类型？绝对不可能。那么酒精呢？
the science is clear when we drink to
科学已经很清楚地表明，当我们饮酒到
the point of having a hangover is that
宿醉的程度时，
dehydration absolutely not the issue is
脱水绝对不是问题所在。问题在于
you have caused significant damage to
你对肠道菌群造成了严重的损害。
your microbiome but the gut is forgiving
但肠道具有恢复能力，
and the choices that you make today
你今天
within 24 hours will have an effect on
在24小时内做出的选择会对
your microbiome I want people to eat a
你的肠道菌群产生影响。我希望人们能够通过一种可以随心所欲、不受限制地进食，同时又能
achieve their weight goals and this is
达到理想体重的饮食方式来实现这一点。这
completely possible by consuming a diet
完全可以通过一种
that's quick one this is really really
快速有效的饮食方式来实现。这真的让
fascinating to me on the back end of our
我很着迷。在我们的
YouTube channel it says that
YouTube频道后台，数据显示，在我们频道开播以来，
frequently over the lifetime of this
经常观看我们
channel haven't yet hit the Subscribe
频道的观众中有69.9%还没有点击订阅
button I just wanted to ask you a favor
按钮。我只是想请你们帮个忙。
it helps this channel so much if you
如果你选择订阅，这对我们频道的帮助非常大，可以
choose to just subscribe helps us scale
帮助我们邀请
the guest helps us scale the production
嘉宾，帮助我们扩大制作规模，也
and it makes this show bigger so if I
能让节目更加精彩。所以，
could ask you for one favor if you've
如果你
watched the show before and you've
之前看过我们的节目，并且喜欢
enjoyed it and you like this episode
它，也喜欢你
that you're currently watching could you
现在正在观看的这一集，请你
please hit the Subscribe button thank
点击订阅按钮。
you so much and I will repay that
非常感谢！我会以
gesture by making sure that everything
实际行动来回报你的支持。 我保证
we do here gets better and better and
我们在这里所做的一切都会越来越好，越来越好，越来越
better and better that is a promise I'm
好，这是我
willing to make you do we have a
愿意向你做出的承诺。威尔博士，我们有
[Music]
音乐方面的
deal Dr will if someone's just clicked
合作吗？如果有人刚刚点击
on this conversation and they they're
进入这个对话，正在
deciding whether to listen or not what
决定是否继续听下去，你会如何
would be the pitch to those people
向他们推销？
what's the benefit if they stick around
如果他们留下来，会有什么好处？
welcome to a uh what I sincerely believe
欢迎收听！我真心相信这将是一次
will be a life transforming conversation
改变你人生的对话，
for you because the issue is that we are
因为问题在于我们
currently Liv living through an epidemic
目前正经历着一场
of gut of gut health issues um if we
肠道健康问题的流行。如果我们
look across the board this is everywhere
放眼全局，就会发现这个问题无处不在，
and it's not just you know uh digestion
而且不仅仅局限于消化，
this is so much more than that we need
它远不止于此。我们
this now more than ever because
现在比以往任何时候都更需要它，因为
ultimately if we want to be healthy
归根结底，如果我们想要成为健康的
humans which to me is one of the highest
人——在我看来，这是
goals that we should hold for ourselves
我们应该为自己设定的最高目标之一——
if we want to be healthy humans we we
我们就
absolutely need a healthy gut microbiome
绝对需要一个健康的肠道菌群来
in order to accomplish that what's your
实现这一目标。你的
sort of academic professional background
学术和专业背景是什么？
oh gosh where do we begin um so uh I
哦，天哪，我们从哪里开始呢？嗯，我
graduated from Vanderbilt University uh
毕业于范德比尔特大学，获得了
with a chemistry degree that was my
化学学位，那是我的
college and um I went to Georgetown
大学。 我去了乔治城大学，
which is one of the top medical schools
那是全美顶尖的医学院之一。
in the country I um spent three years at
我在西北大学做了三年
Northwestern as a as uh Internal
内科
Medicine resident I won the highest
住院医师，
award that they give while there then I
期间获得了他们颁发的最高奖项。后来我担任了
was the chief medical resident and I
总住院医师，并
gastron neurologist in the hospital and
在医院接受了四年的胃肠神经科医生培训，同时
also working on clinical research so
还参与临床研究。所以，
I didn't expect when I finished all this
我当时并没有想到，完成这一切之后，
that I would be continuing to publish
我还会继续发表
papers at any point in my life in the
论文。
future but now in my work with Zoe as
但现在，作为Zoe的
their us medical director I've been
美国医疗总监，我再次
heavily involved in clinical research
深度参与了临床研究。
again you mentioned a big GW there
你刚才提到了乔治城大学的
gastro
胃肠科
enologist what is that uh we are the
医生，那是什么呢？我们是专门研究肠道的
specialists in terms of basically like
专家。
the intestines the gut so if I were to
如果要
summarize it I would say guts and butts
概括的话，我会说肠道和屁股，
guts and butts yeah the conversation
肠道和屁股。是的，
around the gut microbiome and the gut
关于肠道微生物群和肠道
generally has exploded really since what
本身的讨论在2006年到2007年之间爆发式增长。在此之前，
to be fair with you I think as far as
公平地说，据
I'm aware and I'm not that close to
我所知（我和
doctors or hospitals or research I've
医生们的关系并不密切）， 我最近两年，或者说三年，才开始在医院或研究机构
only started hearing about the gut
听到关于肠道
microbiome in the prevalence that I have
微生物群的普及信息。
most people have as it relates to their
大多数人对
health that guy that looks into the
健康最大的误解是什么？就是那种照
mirror and goes I don't like what I see
镜子说“我不喜欢我看到的，
here I don't feel good that's C up they
我感觉不好”的人，他们肚子
they're bloated they've got gut
胀气，肠胃
pains the current sort of line of
疼痛。目前普遍的
thinking will say it is X but there's
思维方式是说这是X，但
something that you believe it is what is
你心里肯定有别的想法。那是什么呢？
that well I think that all of these
我认为所有这些
things ultimately con connect back to
最终都与
our gut microbiome and I think that's
我们的肠道微生物群有关。我认为这正是我们一直以来
missing this entire time you know
缺失的那块拼图。你知道，
there's it was sort of this black box if
它就像一个黑匣子，好像只要
you eat well you will improve your
你吃得好，你的
health if you do this you will improve
健康就会改善；只要你这样做，
your health um what we were missing was
你的健康就会改善。我们缺失的是
the understanding that all of those
理解：所有这些
choices ultimately impact these gut
选择最终都会影响肠道
microbes and by impacting these gut
微生物，而通过影响肠道
microbes you can actually transform the
微生物，你实际上可以改变
physiology within your body gut microbes
你体内的生理机能。肠道微生物，是的，
yeah what is that gut microbes is my
肠道微生物是什么？这是我用比较专业的说法。
nerdy way of talking about these uh
这些
microorganisms that like you can't see
微生物，你
them right now but they're there they're
现在可能看不见，但它们确实存在。
you know if you hold up your thumb
你知道吗？如果你竖起你的拇指，你会发现
literally on your thumb there are as
拇指上的
many microbes as there are people in the
微生物数量和英国的人口数量一样多。
UK really and they cover our entire body
它们覆盖了我们全身，从
from the top of our head to the tip of
头顶到
our toes every single external part of
脚趾，我们身体的每一个外部部位都
our body is covered with these microbes
覆盖着这些微生物。
but the main spot is actually deep
但最主要的部位其实
inside of us which is our colon the
在我们体内深处，也就是我们的结肠，也就是
large intestine in that spot you can
大肠。在那里，你可以
find 38
找到38
trillion now these when I say microbes
万亿个微生物。我说的微生物
it's referring to the fact that they're
是指它们是
microscopic and they're alive it's
微小的、活的，
mostly
主要是
bacteria um in addition to bacteria
细菌。除了细菌，
could also be fungi could be parasites
也可能是真菌、寄生虫或
could be viruses but we have 38 trillion
病毒。但我们结肠里聚集着38万亿个
of these mostly bacteria focused and
微生物，其中大部分是细菌。
concentrated within our colon so when we
所以，当我们
talk about the gut microbiome are really
谈论肠道微生物群时，我们实际上
referring to them how did they get there
指的是它们。它们是怎么来的呢？
so you started in your mother's womb MH
你从母亲的子宫里就开始
into contact with these
接触这些
microbes but um but for the most part
微生物了。现在的证据表明，你从出生就开始接触它们了，但大多数情况下，
you haven't really met them yet until
你并没有真正接触到它们。 直到
the water breaks and in that moment for
羊水破裂的那一刻，
the first time you are exposed to the
你才会第一次接触到这个
world and the world is covered in
世界。这个世界充满了
microbes everything that's alive
微生物，所有生物都有
everything has a microbiome could be a
微生物群落，无论是
plant could be an animal could be an
植物、动物、
insect could be us so when Mom's water
昆虫，还是我们自身。当妈妈的羊水
breaks these microbes then enter into
破裂时，这些微生物就会进入
the uterus and you meet them for the
子宫，你才会第一次见到它们。
first time but you are particularly
尤其是在
exposed to them as you pass through the
通过产道时，你会更加频繁地接触到它们。
canal and this is basically like
这就像
Nature's Way of being like hello welcome
大自然在说：“你好，欢迎
to the world and meet your partner ERS
来到这个世界！认识一下你的伴侣——免疫系统吧！它们将
that'll be with you for the rest of your
陪伴你
life and they're here to help you and
一生，帮助你，
they will make you healthier and this is
让你更健康。”这是
the result of co-evolution that goes
共同进化的结果，可以
back over a billion years we have been
追溯到十亿多年前。我们一直在
evolving and which is crazy because
进化，这很不可思议，因为
humans have only existed for three three
人类存在的时间只有三四
or four million
百万
years but these microbes were the first
年，但这些微生物是
life on the planet and all life evolved
地球上最早的生命，所有生命都
with these microbes and things like for
与这些微生物共同进化。
example our immune system is the product
例如，我们的免疫系统就是
of evolution that started a billion
进化的产物，而这种进化早在
years before humans even existed we
人类出现之前十亿年就开始了。我们
always think of ourselves as one
总是把自己看作一个
organism but you're making the case that
整体，但实际上，你正在创造…… 假设
I'm maybe 36 trillion or whatever you
我体内可能含有36万亿个微生物，或者像你
said organisms in one and we would call
说的那么多，我们会称
you a super organism and that sounds
你为超级生物体，这听起来
like a Marvel character which is cool
像漫威角色，很酷，
and we'll take that but that's actually
我们就这么认为吧。但这其实
completely true because the issue is
完全正确，因为问题在于，
that if we withdrew these microbes from
如果我们从你体内移除这些微生物，比如
you if you were like hypothetically you
假设一下，
know we could talk about the Bubble Boy
我们可以谈谈20世纪70年代的“泡泡男孩”实验。
from um the 19 1970s where they actually
他们真的
did this they tried to have a child live
这么做了，试图让一个患有特定免疫缺陷的孩子生活
in a sterile world because he had a
在无菌环境中。
specific immune deficiency so their
他们的
thought was if we keep him separate from
想法是，如果我们把他与
all the bacteria then he'll never have a
所有细菌隔离开来，他就永远不会有
problem but the issue is that there are
问题。但问题是，
living without microbes because we need
没有微生物的生活是有后果的，因为我们需要
them so and through this process of
它们。通过这种
co-evolution literally from the very
共同进化的过程，从第一个
first human we grew to trust
人类开始，我们就逐渐信任
them and we trusted them with things
它们，并将对我们人类至关重要的事情托付给它们，
our success as humans and we allowed
并允许
them to integrate into our physiology in
它们以某种方式融入我们的生理系统。
a way where once again if we don't have
如果我们没有
them we're in trouble and that includes
它们，我们就麻烦了，这包括
things like digestion breaking down our
消化分解
food which to me is like that's the
食物之类的过程。对我来说， 就像这就是
essence of life like you can't get
生命的本质一样，没有它们，你就无法获得
energy into your body without this and
能量。
they help us to accomplish that but they
它们帮助我们做到这一点，但它们
also train our immune system you know we
也训练我们的免疫系统。你知道，我们
talked a moment ago about what happens
刚才谈到了
when you're born and that's the very
出生时发生的事情，那是
beginning of training your immune system
训练免疫系统的开始。在
life life it has a massive impact on
生命的前三年，它们对
whether or not you develop allergic
你日后是否会患上过敏
issues autoimmune issues down the road
症和自身免疫性疾病有着巨大的影响。
they affect our metabolism our research
它们影响我们的新陈代谢。Zoey 的研究
at Zoey has overwhelmingly shown that
已经充分表明，
they play a critical and essential role
它们
in controlling for example your blood
在控制
sugar your blood fat response after a
血糖、餐后血脂反应等方面发挥着至关重要的作用。它们
meal they affect your
影响你的
mood um literally your energy
情绪，你的精力
levels uh whether or not you suffer from
水平，你是否患有
depression your cognition your memory
抑郁症，
your ability to focus all affected by
你的认知能力、记忆力、注意力等等，所有这些都受到
these microbes they affect our hormones
这些微生物的影响。它们还影响我们的激素水平。
so in women conditions like
因此，在女性中，子宫内膜异位症、多囊卵巢综合征等疾病都与肠道菌群
associated with damage to the gut
受损有关；
microbiome in men erectile
在男性中，勃起功能障碍——
dysfunction which I mean to be honest is
说实话，这个问题并
not talked about
没有得到
enough um perhaps because we've
足够的重视，也许是因为我们对它存在
stigmatized this but this the guys that
偏见。但对于
have this issue this is like the most
有这个问题的人来说，这几乎是
important issue to them and so when you
他们最关心的问题。所以，当你
think about all these things whether it
想到所有这些…… 无论是
be digestion our immune system our
消化、免疫系统、
metabolism our hormones our mood our
新陈代谢、激素水平、情绪还是
brain health like to me this is um uh an
大脑健康，对我来说，这就像是
human health from my perspective as a
从我作为一名医生的角度出发，对人类健康所有重要因素的概述。
medical doctor and is my microbiome
我的微生物组和
different to yours do we all have
你的不一样吗？我们每个人
different sort of jungles inside of
体内的微生物群落都不一样吗？
us we are all different and this is one
我们每个人都不一样，而这正是让
of the things that makes us actually
我们彼此之间产生
profoundly different so to be honest
深刻差异的原因之一。说实话，
it's it's this is mindblowing if we
这真是令人震惊。如果我们
looked at your genetic code and my
比较你的基因序列和我的
genetic code even though clearly we are
基因序列，即使我们显然是
different people we our genetic code
不同的人，我们的基因序列
would be
也会有
99.99% the
99.99%的
same it's a small part of our genetics
相似度，只有一小部分基因在我们
that is different between us as
之间存在差异。
humans but our microbiome these 38
但是，我们体内的微生物组——这38
trillion microbes that are living inside
万亿个微生物——却
of us they can be completely different
可能完全不同。
so as as a classic example let's pretend
举个经典的例子，假设
that you have a twin brother identical
你有一个同卵
twin brother brother mhm all right so
双胞胎兄弟，嗯，好的。
you share the exact same genetic code
你们拥有完全相同的基因序列，
you share the same mother for the vast
拥有同一个母亲，在
majority of cases you would have shared
绝大多数情况下，你们会拥有
the same childhood and largely the same
相同的童年，
upbringing in food and things like this
在饮食等方面也基本相同。
and our research shows that only about
我们的研究表明，只有
even though you come from the exact same
即使你来自同一个
place you would be 75% or more different
地方，你和我的微生物群也只有大约25%是相同的，而75%甚至更多是不同的。
so you and I it's hard to say exactly
所以，很难说你我之间到底有多大区别。比如说，
like if our diet was you know quite
如果我们的饮食非常
similar then we would have a more
相似，那么我们的
similar microbiome but it still would be
微生物群也会比较相似，但即便如此，它们仍然会比
more different than the same and how
完全相同的要
much then so I've got twin we've got
多。那么，到底有多少差异呢？我和双胞胎的
completely different micro gut
肠道微生物群就完全不同，
microbiomes these sort of um microbes
这些微生物
that live inside our bodies how much of
生活在我们体内。我们体内有多少
microbiome can be Associated back to
微生物群与疾病相关呢？
view what percentage of disease do you
你认为有多少比例的疾病与
think links back to the gut
肠道
microbiome well it's hard to say
微生物群有关？很难
globally right it's hard to give an
一概而论，很难给出一个
exact number um you would have to I
确切的数字。我认为，你需要针对具体疾病进行分析才能确定。
but what I would say is this my you know
但我之所以对这个话题如此
the reason that I became very interested
感兴趣，是因为我
in this as a gastron
作为一名胃肠
neurologist is that I was convinced and
神经科医生，确信（而且
I continue to believe this to be true
我仍然坚信）
that every person that walked through
每个来找
the door to see me had a gut microbiome
我看病的人都存在肠道微生物群
problem right people with iral bowel
问题，比如肠易激
syndrome Crohn's disease ulcer of citis
综合征和克罗恩病患者。 溃疡性结肠炎、
celiac disease acid reflux go down the
乳糜泻、胃酸反流……
line every single one of these when we
我们
study them we discover that they have
研究这些疾病时发现，它们都与
gut issues but the other thing if you
肠道问题有关。但还有一点，如果你
expand that one of the things that I
进一步分析，
would always do you know I'm about to go
你会发现，我通常会做的一件事是，当我准备
see a patient I'm going to walk into the
去看病人时，我会走进
room and you take the chart off the door
房间，然后把病历从门上取下来。
right you hear if you're the patient you
如果你是病人，
hear that you're in the room and you
你会听到
hear the chart come off the door and the
病历从门上取下来的声音，
doctor flips it open and what do I do I
医生会打开病历。我会
take a look at their medical
查看他们的
history and when you when you look what
病史，你会发现
you see is a laundry list of conditions
一长串与
the gut microbiome so they're here to
肠道菌群受损相关的疾病。他们来
see me for their digestive problem like
看病是因为消化问题，比如
iral bowel syndrome but when I take a
肠易激综合征，但当我
look I see that they have
查看病史时，我发现他们还有
hyper lipidemia high blood pressure type
高脂血症、高血压、
2 diabetes history of major depression
2型糖尿病、重度抑郁症病史，
uh they may have autoimmune condition
他们可能患有自身免疫性疾病。
right so and then it starts to implicate
然后，病史开始牵涉到一些
these different systems that like we
我们通常
have not classically associated immune
不会与免疫系统（
like autoimmune issues or metabolic
比如自身免疫性疾病）、代谢问题、
issues or cognitive issues or mood
认知问题或情绪
issues we haven't classically Associated
问题联系起来的不同系统。 虽然传统上并未将
those things with the gut microbiome yet
这些因素与肠道微生物群联系起来，但
they are and so to me do I need like for
它们确实存在关联。所以，对于我来说，我需要为
that particular patient do I need a poop
这位特定的病人做粪便
test to tell me that they have a damaged
检查来告诉我他们的
gut absolutely not it's already clear
肠道是否受损吗？绝对不需要，这一点已经很清楚了。那么，
and what's the relationship between our
我们的
gut microbiome and our immune system I
肠道微生物群和免疫系统之间有什么关系呢？我在
was reading in the introduction to your
您的书的引言中读到，
book that 70% of the immune system is is
70%的免疫系统都位于肠道。是的，
yeah the um the walls of your intestine
肠壁
are actually the home of your immune
实际上是免疫
system we classically would think of the
系统的家园。我们通常认为
immune system exists that's not true
免疫系统存在于骨髓中，但这并不完全正确。
that's where the immune the immune cells
免疫细胞在
are born there but then they basically
那里产生，但它们会
immigrate out and then they take up
迁移出来，并在
residence and live within the walls of
肠壁内定居。顺便说一句，
complete sense from an evolutionary
从进化的
perspective because our gut is actually
角度来看，这完全说得通，因为我们的肠道实际上是
the most vulnerable part of our body
我们身体最脆弱的部分，
this is where we come into contact with
是我们与外界接触的地方。
the outside world your skin you may
你可能会
think of that no your skin is a wall
认为皮肤是屏障，但事实并非如此。皮肤是一道屏障，
your gut is the place where actually you
肠道才是你
are making decisions do I absorb and
做出决定的地方——我是否吸收并
allow this into the body or do I reject
允许这些物质进入体内，还是我拒绝
and keep it outside and in order to help
并阻止它们进入体内。 它位于肠道外，为了帮助它进入
system there but the other thing that we
体内，我们需要免疫系统，但我们需要的另一件事
need is we need a barrier we need
是一道屏障，我们需要
something to basically um uh section off
某种东西来将
the inside of the intestines and keep
肠道内部与外界隔开，使之保持
things separate so what we have is
分离。
called the epithelial layer and this is
这道屏障叫做上皮层，尽管
this is in our body it is just a single
它对我们身体的重要性不言而喻，但它只是一层
together by this kind of cement called
由紧密连接（一种类似水泥的物质）粘合在一起的细胞。紧密连接的一侧
one side is 70% of your immune system on
是人体70%的免疫系统，
the other side are 38 trillion microbes
另一侧是38万亿的微生物。
and when this barrier breaks down this
当这道屏障被破坏时，
is how things that are inside your
肠道内的病原体
intestines can get access to your body
就能进入体内，
um get into your bloodstream potentially
进入血液，可能
cause a whole body
导致全身
infection and then the immune system is
感染。这时，免疫系统就会
forced to react and when this is like we
被迫做出反应。当我们感染时，
this is why we have an immune system to
免疫系统的作用就显得尤为重要，它能
protect us in that setting but what's
保护我们免受感染。然而，
happening in the 21st century what
在21世纪，
started in the 20th
始于20
century is chronic
世纪的慢性
inflammation and chronic inflamation is
炎症正在兴起。慢性炎症是
gut barrier breaks down now we are
肠道屏障被破坏的结果。 现在，肠道屏障正在崩溃，一些
aren't supposed to get access and the
不应该进入我们身体的东西也随之进入体内。
result is that the immune system stays
结果就是免疫系统
perpetually active because it is
持续活跃，因为它
constantly trying to clear stuff out
不断地试图清除这些物质，
because the barrier is broken and for
因为屏障已经破损。对于
those who are wondering so Dr B then how
那些想知道的人，B医生，那么
do we how do we fix the barrier not to
我们该如何修复这个屏障呢？我不是要
put the question into your mouth Stephen
你来问，Stephen，
but please do the answer is the
但请你回答一下。
microbes the answer is the microbes
答案是微生物，
because they are the stewards of the gut
因为它们是肠道
barrier they help to repair it every
屏障的守护者。它们帮助修复肠道屏障，每
three or four days you actually
三四天，你
completely transform and recreate your
的肠道屏障就会彻底改变并重建。
gut barrier so it's not the one that you
所以，你现在
were born with it's the one that you
拥有的不是你与生俱来的屏障，而是你
developed in the last three or four days
在过去三四天内形成的屏障。
and you will turn that over and when it
你会不断地更新它，而当它
turns over we need these gut microbes to
更新时，我们需要这些肠道微生物来
help us to form a strong gut barrier so
帮助我们形成一个强大的肠道屏障。正
because it's constantly turning over
因为肠道屏障在不断更新，所以
again the microbes when you when you
微生物才发挥作用，它们至关重要。再次强调，
reference microbes you're talking about
微生物指的是
viruses that exist in our in our guts
存在于我们肠道中的细菌、酵母、寄生虫和病毒。
and how long do they live for you said
它们能活多久？你说
they turn over in three days does that
它们三天更新一次，那是不是
mean that they live for three days
意味着它们通常只能活三天？
typically so the uh the gut barrier
所以肠道屏障
turns over every 3 days yeah yeah so and
每三天更新一次？是的，是的。
those are human cells so those are not
那些是人体细胞，所以它们不是
the microbes okay so those are your
微生物。好的，所以那些是你的
human cells keeping the the microbes
人体细胞，它们将微生物
separate from your immune system and
与你的免疫系统和
your body MH um these microbes they are
身体隔离开来。嗯，这些微生物几乎
um turning over like literally every 20
每20
minutes they're dying every 20 minutes
分钟就更新一次，它们每20分钟就死亡一次。嗯，
so well not necessarily dying
不一定是死亡，而是复制，复制。
replicating replicating okay right and
好的。
so if we think about this if we had if
如果我们想想，假设
you had one microbe in your intestines
你现在肠道里只有一种微生物，
right now and we feeded something
我们喂它一些东西，不管是
whatever it may be good thing bad thing
好东西还是坏东西，
whatever 24 hours from now that microb
24小时后，这种微生物
will have spawned at least a new
至少会繁殖出一种新的
microbes so if you think about the power
微生物。想想这种力量，它能
that exists there to amplify choices
放大选择，
starting with one and ending 24 hours
从一个开始，24小时
later with a thousand it's crazy there's
后变成一千种，真是太疯狂了。你
reframing in the introduction of your
在书的引言中有一个非常有趣的重新构建框架，它
book which is really simple but it does
很简单，但确实
cause you to I think it's a really
能让你思考。我认为这是一个非常
powerful frame to Think Through about
强大的框架，值得我们去思考
what we eat and how we eat which is
什么。 我们吃什么，怎么吃，这其中就涉及到了食物。比如，
where you say that um each of us
你提到我们每个人
consumes an average of 1.3 kg of food
平均每天消耗1.3公斤食物，
per day keeping the math simple that's
简单算一下，
475 kilos of food per year meaning we'll
一年就是475公斤，也就是说我们一生中会
consume about
消耗大约
36,300 kilos of food during our
36300公斤食物。
lifetime and in contrast to the couple
相比之下，
of milligrams of medicine that we take
我们每天服用的药物剂量只有几毫克，这
it really makes you realize that food is
让我们意识到，食物
in fact the medicine that we're feeding
实际上就是我们
our body at all times we think we sort
时刻滋养身体的良药。我们通常把食物和药物区
of compartmentalize food over here as
分开来，食物是用来
this energy source that quenches hunger
满足饥饿感的能量来源，而
and then we have medicine over here to
药物则是用来
fix stuff yeah but in fact you're doing
解决问题的。但事实上，我们
36,000 kilos of food in your lifetime so
一生中要消耗36300公斤的食物，所以，对
sway on your medical your sort of
你的身体
physiological health and your your your
健康、生理健康以及
gut health is of course the food the
肠道健康影响最大的当然是食物，
food is the medicine well I think that
食物就是良药。我认为这一点
there's two important takeaways from
有两个重要的启示，
that because there was a study actually
因为2014年发表在《自然》杂志上的一项研究
that changed my life in 2014 that came
改变了我的人生。《
Nature which is literally the top
自然》是顶尖的医学
journal on the planet and um uh the
期刊。 这项研究的
author was Warren David from Duke
作者是杜克大学的沃伦·戴维。
University and you have to understand if
你要知道，
we go back this is almost 10 years ago
这已经是近十年前的事了。当时
go in this moment we didn't know if food
我们并不知道食物是否会
changed microbes in humans we didn't
改变人类的微生物群，我们对此一无所知。
know this this is new
这是个全新的
information we knew it in mice but it's
发现，我们之前在小鼠身上观察到过这种现象，但
not the same mice are not humans um so
小鼠毕竟不是人类。为了
what they did to try to prove this is
验证这一点，
they put people on uh diametrically
他们让受试者分别采用两种截然
opposed diets so a completely 100%
相反的饮食：一种是完全纯素
plant-based diet versus a completely
饮食，另一种是完全
100% animal-based diet it was only a
纯素饮食。这项
5-day study which is interesting because
研究只有短短五天，这很有意思，因为短短
within 5 days you can actually see
五天内就能看到
massive results and the key one of the
显著的结果。
key takeaways from this study is that
这项研究的关键结论之一是：
the choices that you make today within
选择…… 你今天在
24 hours will have an effect on your
24小时内的饮食习惯会对你的
microbiome in that study when they
肠道菌群产生影响。那项研究表明，当
changed a person's diet 24 hours later
改变一个人的饮食后，24小时后
you could already see things underway
就能看到肠道菌群开始发生
shifting so now the other thing to keep
变化。所以，现在需要记住的另一点
in mind here is that I think is really
是，我认为非常
important is the gut is forgiving I mean
重要的一点是，肠道具有一定的“宽容度”。我的意思是，
to a degree you can only beat it up so
你只能在一定程度上“虐待”它，
much but the gut is forgiving so this
但肠道确实具有这种宽容度。这
doesn't mean that there are foods that
并不意味着有些食物可以吃，有些食物不能吃——
everything is on the table but what we
所有食物都可以吃。我们
want is we want to create a weight or a
想要的是增加高质量食物的摄入量，或者说
disproportionate consumption of those
不成比例地摄入这些食物，
high quality foods because when we do we
因为当我们这样做时，我们
are lifting these microbes up explain
就提升了这些微生物的水平。解释一下
that process of food and the impact it
食物对微生物的影响：这就像给
watering certain microbes is that a way
某些微生物浇水一样，可以这样
to think about it in simple terms these
理解吗？简单来说，这些
microbes are as alive as you and I are
微生物和我们一样都是活的，
Stephen and and we need to eat um if I
斯蒂芬，我们需要进食。如果我
don't eat I get quite hangry and they do
不吃东西，我会很饿，它们也会。
too and but it turns out that the reason
但事实证明，它们之所以会成为肠道菌群的“
that they took up residents because they
居民”，是因为它们
could have been anywhere they could have
可能存在于任何地方，它们可能
stayed inside soil or lived on a plant
生活在土壤中，也可能生活在……
or something like that they chose to
它们选择
live inside of you and the reason why
生活在你的体内，可能是植物之类的东西。它们之所以待在
they are inside your colon is because
你的结肠里，是因为
they get access to nutrition you do that
它们能从你那里获得营养。
for them you go out you find food and
你外出寻找食物，然后把食物
you deliver that to them whatever goes
送到它们面前。
into your mouth whatever it may be it
无论你吃进嘴里的东西是什么，
will come into contact with these
都会接触到这些
microbes and they will consume it and
微生物，它们会消耗这些食物，而
and this becomes their energy source
这便成为它们的能量来源。
because they are alive they need energy
因为它们活着，就需要能量。
so but the choices that you make impact
所以，你的选择会影响
which microbes get to
哪些微生物能吃到
eat so not every single microbe likes
食物。并非所有微生物都喜欢羽衣
kale not every single microbe likes
甘蓝，也并非所有微生物都喜欢
sugar but there are some that like sugar
糖，但有些微生物喜欢糖，
and some that like kale and when you
有些喜欢羽衣甘蓝。当你
make these choices whatever it may be
做出这些选择时，无论是什么，
those choices ultimately are going to
这些选择最终都会
feed specific families of microbes lift
滋养特定的微生物家族，提升
them up and allow them to thrive so when
它们的数量，让它们茁壮成长。所以，当
we talk about you know improving dietary
我们谈到改善膳食
quality and you hear me talk about this
质量时，你会在我2018年开始公开分享的“纤维驱动”理念中听到我谈到这一点，这
2018 um and the book came out in 2020 or
本书于2020年出版。或者，
if you listen to Tim Spector who
如果你听听蒂姆·斯佩克特（Tim Spector）的演讲，他
published the paper that I'm about to
发表了我即将
talk about um the science is clear the
谈到的那篇论文，科学已经明确指出
way to lift the microbes up is by eating
提升微生物数量的方法。 蒂姆·
a variety of plants now in Tim spectre's
斯佩克特（Tim Spectre）
paper that originally came out it's
最初发表的论文（
called the American gut project but by
名为“美国肠道计划”）指出，通过食用多种植物可以改善肠道菌群。
the way the British gut project was a
顺便一提，“英国肠道计划”是这项
the study in that study um you have to
研究的重要组成部分。在这项研究中，
understand the magic number that they
他们得出的神奇数字
came to was
是
30 a lot of that had to do with just the
30。这很大程度上与
technique that they were using to
他们使用的
measure it doesn't mean that 29 is bad
测量技术有关，但这并不意味着29就不好，
and 30 is
30就
fantastic it's all on a spectrum 30 30
很好，这是一个连续谱。
different plants per week mhm yeah 30
每周30种不同的植物，嗯，是的，
different plants per week so the key is
每周30种不同的植物。所以关键在于
we want varieties of plants and every
我们要摄入多种植物，每
single plant's Choice ultimately is fuel
一种植物最终都是
for a healthy gut microbiome so that's
健康肠道菌群的燃料。这些植物包括
fruits vegetables whole grains seeds
水果、蔬菜、全谷物、种子、
nuts and legumes it's not just veggies
坚果和豆类，不仅仅是蔬菜，也
it's not just kale and to me like one of
不仅仅是羽衣甘蓝。对我来说，
whether it be as a medical doctor or as
无论是作为一名医生还是作为
an author I want to meet people where
一名作家，我一直努力做到的一点是，我想了解人们的实际情况。比如，
they are so like if it were if I were
如果我在
Consulting with you I want to know where
咨询你，我想了解
you stand right now and then we're going
你目前的状况。 我们要
to set realistic goals because so for a
设定切合实际的目标，因为对于一个
per week which which by the way is more
每周吃10种不同植物的人来说（顺便说一句，这
than I was eating 10 years ago to go to
比我10年前吃的还多），
30 instantly that would be quite hard
一下子增加到30种是相当困难的，
and when it's hard it's more likely to
而当目标难以实现时，就更容易难以
unsustainable I would go from 10 to 15
坚持。我会先从10种增加到15种，
and when you hit 15 I would be
当你达到15种的时候，我会
celebrating how many plants does the
庆祝一下。
America the UK Europe do you know uh I
你知道吗？在西方世界，比如美国、英国和欧洲，普通人平均每周吃多少种植物？我
believe in the American gut project the
记得美国肠道项目（American Gut Project）的数据显示，
average person it was a minority of
普通人
people that were hitting 30 per week and
每周大约吃10到15种植物，只有少数人能达到30种。
that's the
这很
it's interesting when I I did my Zoe
有意思。我做了Zoe
test I got my results back and it did
测试，结果显示
say that I had quite a narrow gut
我的肠道
microbiome in comparison to my partner
菌群比我的伴侣要窄很多。
and I was thinking about this I was like
我一直在想这个问题，
you know whenever we go somewhere
你知道，每次
whenever we go to a restaurant she
我们去餐厅，她总是
orders new things all the time and if
点新菜，而
you look at our fridge it's like tahini
你看看我们的冰箱，里面全是芝麻酱之类的东西，
and this and all this like all these
各种各样的
plants especially in the top part of our
植物，尤其是在…… 我们冰箱最上面那层
fridge it's all like fermented stuff she
全是发酵食品，她
eats like she's a like a rabbit or she
吃得就像兔子一样，或者说
just eats anything and she eats diverse
她什么都吃，而且吃的
food food and she orders new things and
食物种类很丰富，她还会点一些新奇的东西。
then there's me yeah I like what I like
然后我呢，嗯，我喜欢吃我喜欢的。
and if I go to a restaurant anyone
如果我去餐厅，任何
that's been to a restaurant with me like
跟我去过
three times could order for me because
三次的人都能帮我点菜，因为
they know um until I got my zuro results
他们了解我。直到我拿到Zuro的检测结果，结果相当
back and it was it was pretty alarming
惊人，
cuz she had her my crbs were like a like
因为她的肠道菌群就像
the Amazon rainforest nice and mine were
亚马逊雨林一样丰富，而我的就像……
like you know I park at the End of the
你知道，我把车停在街尾……
Street H you know I think that it's
你知道，我觉得从
important to start with food that you
自己喜欢的食物开始很重要。是的，
like yeah we're all like that what you
我们都像你
described but the issue is finding that
描述的那样，但问题在于找到
motivation to push yourself to me this
动力去推动自己。对我来说，这就是关键所在。
like again this was a black box we
就像之前肠道菌群是个黑匣子，我们对它一无所知，只有一些关于
microbiome we just had like nutritional
营养的
ideas being tossed at us now this is
理论被抛给我们。现在，它
filling in the gaps where it's like hold
填补了这些空白，让我们意识到，
up no nutrition affects the microbes the
营养不会影响微生物，
microbes affect us as humans now we can
微生物也会影响我们人类。 现在我们可以把
connect those dots and to me I find this
这些点联系起来了。对我来说，知道这一点
very empowering and motivating to know
非常鼓舞人心，也很有动力。
that that exists and to know that those
知道
choices every single meal is an
每一餐的选择都是
opportunity to follow this concept and
遵循这个理念、丰富
add more diversity to your plate but the
餐盘的机会，这本身就很有启发意义。但
other thing is you mentioned that your
你提到你的
partner is eating fermented food that's
伴侣在吃发酵食品，这其实是
is a lost start people have not been
一个好的开始。
consuming fermented food in the western
在西方世界，人们很少食用发酵食品。目前的
world and the research is quite clear
研究非常明确，
and standing out at this point that
而且尤其引人注目的是，
study out of Stanford University
斯坦福大学一项有趣的
randomized control trial the
随机对照试验表明，
intervention was to add fermented food
干预措施是在
to the diet in people that had not been
不
consuming fermented food and what they
食用发酵食品的人群的饮食中添加发酵食品。
found eight weeks later is that they had
八周后，研究人员发现，这些人的
increased the diversity within their gut
肠道菌群多样性增加了。
microbiome what does that mean if your
如果你的
microbiome is the park at the End of the
肠道菌群就像街尾的公园，那么
Street adding fermented food we can we
添加发酵食品
can make it into a jungle give me some
就能把它变成一片丛林。请举一些
examples of fermented foods and what is
发酵食品的例子，并解释一下“发酵”的含义。
mean well uh first of all we we
首先，我们
mentioned that all all life on this
提到地球上所有生命都
planet has a microbiome so there was an
拥有微生物群。 一项
interesting study where they analyzed
研究分析了
the microbiome of apples and discovered
苹果的微生物组，发现
that when you eat an apple like you just
当你吃一个苹果时——比如你只是从
fruit bowl um that Apple has about a 100
果盘里拿一个——这个苹果里大约有1亿个
million microbes that are a of it so
微生物。这些
they're already there and those microbes
微生物一直存在于苹果中，
helping it to grow from a flower to a
帮助它从花朵生长
fruit okay so um now these microbes they
成果实。这些微生物
are also involved in the life cycle of
也参与了苹果的生命周期。
that Apple so when the Apple goes to
当苹果开始
spoil the microbes are the ones doing
腐烂时，正是这些微生物导致了腐烂。
that in fact I would argue that when
事实上，
food spoils I actually find that
我认为食物腐烂反而令人
reassuring if food doesn't spoil we
欣慰。如果食物不腐烂，我们反而
should be
应该
concerned the microbes are helping to
担心，因为微生物可能正在
facilitate that spoilage that takes
促进食物的腐烂。这是
place and that's because the Earth is
因为地球正在
taking it back it's this it's the cycle
收回食物，这是
of life that's going to turn into
生命的循环，最终会变成
dirt right now fermentation is where we
泥土。发酵是我们控制
actually grab that process and we
这个过程的关键，
control it almost like a magician we're
就像魔术师一样，我们
shaping it and what we're having is
塑造着它。
we're empowering certain
我们赋予某些
microbes to protect that food so it does
微生物力量，使它们能够保护食物，
not spoil and they transform it so if
防止其腐烂，并转化食物。 所以，如果
you were to take cabbage um you know you
你要处理卷心菜，嗯，你知道，你
don't need to do anything special to
不需要对卷心菜做任何特殊处理，
this cabbage you literally just buy
你只需要
cabbage perhaps at your farmers's Market
在农贸市场买一些卷心菜，
chop it up put it into a mason jar pack
切碎，放进一个玻璃罐里，装好，
it in there and add a sea salt brine
然后加入海盐水，或者说
solution a saltwater
盐
solution and you basically put this into
水溶液，基本上就是把这个罐子放在一个
you know a nice cool
阴凉的
space give it a week you will have
地方，放一个星期，你就能得到
sauerkraut sauerkraut is not salty
酸菜了。酸菜不是咸的
cabbage it's tart it's bitter uh it's
卷心菜，它是酸的，有点苦，嗯，有点
acidic um it's delicious when you make
酸味，嗯，它很美味。你
it yourself it is completely different
自己做的酸菜和
than the sauerkraut that I grew up on
我
that came from a can which was soft and
从小吃的罐头酸菜完全不同，罐头酸菜又软又
disgusting so this is what fermentation
难吃。这就是发酵，
is it's
它是
transformation the microbes specifically
微生物（特别是
bacteria and yeasts are transforming the
细菌和酵母）转化
food for us and when they do this they
食物的过程。微生物在转化食物的同时也在消耗养分，所以它们会变得更
so because they eat they grow stronger
强壮，数量也会
and they multiply so you are creating a
增加。因此，你创造出的
food that is high in microbes which we
食物富含微生物，我们
could call
可以称之为
probiotics it has been transformed to
益生菌。它已经转化，
unlock the
释放出
nutrition which we could call prebiotics
营养，我们可以称之为益生元。
preotic are the parts of our food that
益生元是我们食物中
actually feed the microbes inside of us
真正滋养我们体内微生物的部分，它们
it's their food
是微生物的食物，
prebiotics and they are releasing new
也就是益生元。这些微生物会释放新的
chemicals that can have beneficial
化学物质，
effects on your body which we call call
对你的身体有益，我们称之为
postbiotics you find all of this in that
后生元。你可以在一罐酸菜里找到所有这些，
sauerkraut so that to me is a superfood
所以在我看来，酸菜是一种超级食物。酸菜、泡菜，或者其他腌菜，都属于超级食物。
vinegar and call it a day cucumber true
顺便说一下，腌菜并不是用醋做的。醋是发酵的产物，但腌菜从来不是那种加点黄瓜和醋就完事儿的。真正的黄瓜
pickles are meant to be that you take
腌菜是这样的：你把
the cucumbers you don't skin them you
黄瓜去皮，
allow the microbes that are on the
让表面的微生物发挥
surface to do their job and you put them
作用，然后把它们
into a saltwater solution with some you
放在盐水里，加一些莳
know some dill some garlic black pepper
萝、大蒜、黑胡椒
corns and a couple days later you will
粒，几天后你就
have a pickle I want to make sure I'm
得到腌黄瓜了。我想确保我
super clear on those three biotics that
完全理解你提到的这三种生物：
you mentioned so prebiotics are the food
益生元是
microbes probiotics are the microbes
微生物的食物，益生菌是微生物本身。 益
themselves and then postbiotics are the
生元和后生元是
that the microbes make is that roughly
微生物产生的化合物，这种说法大致
accurate that's roughly accurate and
正确，大致正确。但需要
there's a minor caveat which is that for
注意的是，
these things Prebiotic and probiotic
益生元和益生菌必须
they have to have beneficial effects on
对
humans in order to count okay so we
人体有益才能被认可。我们
can't call it a Prebiotic because it has
不能仅仅因为
just an effect on microbes sugar has an
糖对微生物有影响就称之为益生元，糖
effect on microbes that's not a preotic
对微生物也有影响，但那不是益生元。
probotics now the original conception of
益生菌也是如此。
probotics that most of us have it comes
我们大多数人最初接触的益生菌概念
from a capsule right and the reason why
来自胶囊，之所以
we can call it that is because we have
这样称呼，是因为
demonstrated through clinical studies
临床研究表明，
that capsule have been proven to be
胶囊中含有的特定细菌或酵母菌（在某些情况下）已被证明
beneficial to humans so the Prebiotic is
对人体有益。所以益生元是一种
a food the probiotic is actually alive
食物，益生菌是活的，是的，
yep and then the postbiotic is not alive
而后生元不是活的，它是
that's a compound that's produced by the
由活的微生物产生的化合物。
the key with all of this is the
关键在于后生元，
postbiotic so one of the and and these
它们
can be things that are completely
可以
beneficial and good to us as humans an
对我们人类完全有益。
example of this are the short chain
例如…… 这些是短链
fatty acids short chain fatty acids are
脂肪酸。短链脂肪酸是
the product of consuming fiber or
食用纤维或
resistant starches and they come into
抗性淀粉的产物，它们会
contact with your microbes again you
与你的微生物接触。
would not be able to get these if you
如果你是无菌的，你就无法获得这些。
were sterile can I just drink them in a
我可以喝罐装的
can postbiotics is there not a can of
后生元吗？没有罐装的
postbiotics that I can just drink well
后生元可以喝吗？
so they're coming out now with
现在市面上出现了一些
supplements that um are these
补充剂，这些补充剂
postbiotics in some
在某些情况下是后生元。
cases okay and uh the issue that I've
我
taken with them and I've actually
遇到的问题是，我实际上也
discussed with some people within the
和一些
supplement industry let's not assume
保健品行业的人士讨论过，我们不能假设
that that's going to do the exact same
它能达到与
thing that eating a high-fiber diet is
高纤维饮食完全相同的效果，它们
going to do it's not the same so let's
并不相同。那么我们来
then talk about what happens with those
谈谈这些后生元的作用。
I'm assuming that the postbiotics um
我假设后生元
compounds are the things that have the
化合物是
health all the health benefits so the
所有健康益处的来源。
reason why the gut microbiome is so
肠道微生物群如此健康，这些
healthy the reason why these microbes
微生物
are so beneficial is because they
如此有益的原因在于它们
produce postbiotics and these
产生后生元，而这些
postbiotics help our body in various
后生元以各种方式帮助我们的身体。
ways yes so we uh mentioned earlier we
是的，我们之前提到过，我们一直在
were discussing how we have this gut
讨论…… 肠道
barrier that's key to protecting our
屏障是保护我们
immune system and I mentioned that the
免疫系统的关键，我之前提到过，
the microbes are the stewards of that of
微生物是这道屏障的守护者。
are produced by these bacteria that
这些细菌产生的后生元，也就是短链脂肪酸（如乳酸、乙酸和丙酸），能够
builds the wall when you want to build
构建这道屏障。当你想增强
your wall and protect your body and
屏障、保护身体、
reduce inflammation you need more of
减少炎症时，你需要更多的这些物质。但这
this now it's not that's not the only
并非
thing that they do those postbiotic
它们唯一的作用。这些后生元
short chain fatty acids also directly
短链脂肪酸还能
affect your immune system directly
直接影响免疫系统和
affect your metabolism cross the get
新陈代谢，它们可以
into your bloodstream pass throughout
进入血液循环，遍布
your entire body cross the blood brain
全身，甚至穿过血脑屏障。
barrier they have the ability to
它们能够
actually get access to your
进入
brain and can affect your brain and we
大脑并影响大脑。我们
could talk about different ways that
可以讨论它们发挥作用的不同方式，
that they can do that but the point is
但重点在于，
that this is what um really matters
这才是真正重要的。
because the microbes produce these short
因为微生物产生的
chain fatty acids and these short chain
这些短链
fatty acids have healing effects
脂肪酸对全身都有修复作用。
throughout the entire body and when we
当我们
when we see human studies looking at
看到关于膳食
fiber consumption and showing us how
纤维摄入量的人体研究，并看到膳食
beneficial fiber is to us as humans
纤维对人类的益处时，
the Reon I want everyone to understand
我想让大家明白，膳食纤维对
as humans is because fiber comes into
人类有益的原因在于它能
contact with microbes and those microbes
与微生物接触。 这些微生物会
release short chain fatty acids that's
释放短链脂肪酸，这就是
what's happening metabolism metabolism
新陈代谢正在发生的事情。
is the I've been learning a little bit
我最近一直在学习一些
about metabolism recently when people
关于新陈代谢的知识。人们
think of metabolism they think of the
想到新陈代谢时，通常会想到
speed in which I process my food so
我消化食物的速度。所以
people in society say I've got a high
人们常说
metabolism which means they're probably
新陈代谢快的人可能比较
going to be quite skinny a low
瘦，而新陈代谢慢的人
going to take longer to process my food
消化食物的速度可能比较慢。那么，
relationship between my gut and my
肠道和
metabolism and have I def I've probably
新陈代谢之间究竟有什么关系呢？我之前对
defined metabolism wrong there but what
新陈代谢的定义可能不太准确。
is the relationship well metabolism is
新陈代谢
basically dealing with the currency of
本质上就是能量的流通，它是
that drives us as humans and so how do
驱动我们人类的引擎。那么，
these microbes affect our metabolism
这些微生物是如何影响我们的新陈代谢的呢？
well we have uh research at Zoe looking
我们在Zoe公司有一项名为“
at this directly called the predict one
预测一”的
study and in that we were looking at
研究，专门研究这个问题。在这项研究中，我们探讨了
like what is the thing that tells me
什么因素可以
predicts what your blood sugar response
预测你
is going to be to this food or your
对某种食物的血糖反应，或者餐后你的
blood fat response after a meal and when
血脂反应。当
you start to line these things up
你把这些因素放在一起比较时，你会发现
they're individually different they're
它们各自不同，
not the same but if you look at both of
并不相同。但是，如果你综合考虑这两者，你会发现
them the gut microbiome plays an
肠道微生物群扮演着
essential and critical role in each so
至关重要的角色。
in other words if we know what your gut
换句话说，如果我们知道你的肠道
microbes are then that empowers us to be
微生物是什么，就能
able to understand why you have high
更好地理解你为什么会出现高
blood sugar why you have low blood sugar
血糖或低血糖。
now if we want to get super nerdy and
如果我们想更深入地探讨一下背后的原理，
how this is actually happening it does
这在
come back in many ways to these short
很多方面都与短
chain fatty acids they're not the only
链脂肪酸有关。当然，我们并非只关注短链脂肪酸，
thing we're you know in some ways we're
在某些方面，我们可能
reducing it a little bit too much so I
摄入过量了。所以我
just want to be clear to everyone
想澄清一点，还有
there's other things going on too but
其他因素在起作用。但
these short chain fatty acids they have
这些短链脂肪酸能够
the ability to basically activate
激活
certain receptors and cells that will
某些受体和细胞，从而提高
basically like allow us to have more
我们对
sensitivity to insulin to reduce fat
胰岛素的敏感性，减少脂肪
storage to enhance fat burning so at the
储存，促进脂肪燃烧。所以，
end of the day when we think about these
当我们考虑这些代谢
sort of measures of metabolism because
指标时，比如
there's certain things blood sugar
血糖
response blood fat cholesterol levels um
反应、血脂、胆固醇水平、
uh visceral OB visceral osity mean
内脏脂肪（指
meaning like fat that exists around our
存在于我们
stomach when you look at all these
腹部周围的脂肪），肠道微生物在调节所有这些
things the gut microbes play an
指标中都发挥着
essential role in regulating every
至关重要的作用，
single one of them and the short chain
而短链
fatty acids tend to be the key I read in
脂肪酸正是其中的关键因素。 我在
your book that 60% of poop is bacteria
你的书中读到，粪便中有60%是细菌，
yeah which would just blew my mind yeah
这简直让我震惊。
and I think that this is an important
我认为这是一个非常重要的
conversation to have because we have
话题，因为我们对
stigmatized poop we're not allowed to
粪便存在偏见，我们甚至不被允许
look in the bowl we should be looking in
查看便盆。但我们应该查看
the bowl and the reason why is because
便盆，原因在于，
if I were a
如果我是一名
cardiologist I would come over and I
心脏病专家，我会过来
would check your pulse I would listen to
检查你的脉搏，听听
your heart and those Vital Signs would
你的心跳，这些生命体征能让
allow me to have an idea of how you're
我大致了解
level your cardiovascular health all
你的心血管健康状况。如果
right I'm a gastrologist if I want to
我是一名肠胃科医生，如果我想
know the basics of what's going on with
了解
you and your body I want I need to know
你身体的基本状况，我需要知道
how you're
你的
pooping and what your poop looks like
排便情况和粪便的形态，
because 60% of it is microbial in origin
因为粪便中有60%是微生物产生的，它
because it is not just the excrement of
不仅仅是
your food what your poop looks like
食物残渣。观察粪便的形态
allows me to have insights into your gut
能让我了解你的肠道
health and we've actually proven this
健康状况。事实上，我们已经证实了这一点，
we've actually proven this at Zoe
我们在Zoe诊所已经证实了这一点，
because what we found we did a study
因为我们做了一项
called um
名为“
blue poo and we fed people blue muffins
蓝色粪便”的研究。 我们让人们吃蓝色松饼，
it had a blue food dye and basically
里面加了蓝色食用色素。方法
it's quite simple you eat the muffins
很简单：吃掉松饼，
and then you wait to see when they show
然后等着看它们什么时候
up in the toilet bowl and based upon
出现在马桶里。根据
that time which is basically your gut
这个时间（也就是你的肠道
Transit time how long it takes for the
传输时间，
blue dye to pass through your
蓝色色素通过
intestines we could tell you um what's
肠道所需的时间），我们可以告诉你
going on with your gut
你的肠道
microbiome we could talk about
菌群状况，可以讨论
cardiovascular risk we could talk about
心血管风险，可以讨论
visceral
内脏
fat all quite simply tied to your gut
脂肪，所有这些都与你
Transit time based upon eating a Blue
吃蓝色松饼后的肠道传输时间有关。
Muffin so these things many of these um
所以，
things that you and I are discussing
你我今天讨论的很多事情，
today whether it be the gut connecting
无论是肠道
to our metabolism our immune system or
与我们新陈代谢、免疫系统或
whatever it may
其他任何方面的联系，
be we can connect them back to these
都可以与这些
simple measures like what does your poop
简单的指标联系起来，比如你的粪便是什么样子，
look like or um or how long does it take
或者
for you to have a bomb movement the gut
你排便需要多长时间——肠道
Transit time that's super fascinating I
传输时间。这非常有趣，我也
do want to talk about poop as well but
想谈谈粪便，但是，
um the gut Transit time yeah that's the
肠道传输时间，就是
time it takes from a muffin to go from
松饼从
my lips to the toilet bowl yes and is a
我的嘴到马桶所需的时间。是的，
high gut Transit time better than a low
肠道传输时间越长越好。 比低
have a high gut a good gut Transit time
肠道蠕动时间更重要。那么，是什么决定了我的肠道蠕动时间是快
or a not so good one yeah so gut Transit
还是慢呢？肠道蠕动
time is a
时间是衡量
of this entire digestive system the
整个消化系统健康状况的一个个人指标。顺便说一下，
way instead of like eating beets or
之所以用蓝色染料而不是吃甜菜根之类的食物，
something like that is that the blue dye
是因为蓝色染料
we have like clinically validated this
已经过临床验证。
so this this paper was published in the
这项研究发表在《
journal gut which is the top European
肠道》（Gut）杂志上，这是欧洲顶尖的
gastron neurology
胃肠神经学
journal and there's a couple specific
期刊。
time points that we can use to sort of
我们可以使用几个特定的​​时间点来判断肠道蠕动时间。
cut off these measures um the first is
第一个是
14 hours if you are less than 14 hours
14小时，如果少于14小时，说明肠道蠕动
that is very
非常
fast the other is 58 hours if you are
快；第二个是58小时，如果
more than 58 hours that's very
超过58小时，说明肠道蠕动非常
slow all right so you eat these muffins
慢。好了，你吃这些松饼，
and then you basically just record when
然后记录
did they show up and the average person
它们出现的时间。一般来说，人们会在
is somewhere on the range of 24 hours or
24小时或
48 Hours typically one or two days after
48小时之间，通常是在吃完松饼后的一两天内
start to see this and those are both
开始看到这些痕迹，这两个时间点都被
considered to be normal now if we were
认为是正常的。现在，如果我们把
to break these things out into less than
这些时间点分开来看…… 不到
14 hours more than 58 hours or you know
14小时，超过58小时，或者你知道，
these two sort of Peaks at 24 and 48 we
这两个峰值分别出现在24小时和48小时。
what you start to see is that this is
你会发现，这分为
four groups and these four groups every
四组，每组人群的
different in terms of their gut
肠道
microbiome a little bit different in
菌群和
terms of their gut diversity and we can
肠道多样性都略有不同。我们可以
make associations between these things
将这些差异
and what people are eating so the high
与人们的饮食联系起来。高
fiber consumers are all showing up in
纤维饮食者都出现在
the middle which means normal and the
中间，也就是正常范围内；而
low fiber consumers are the people that
低纤维饮食者则
are showing up on the outside and it
出现在最外侧。这
brings us to one of the properties of
引出了纤维一个非常有趣的特性：
is that whether you have Di diarhea or
无论你是腹泻还是
constipation there's only one thing that
便秘，只有一件事
can correct both of those diarrhea and
可以同时纠正这两种情况。腹泻和
constipation are both fixed with dietary
便秘都可以通过膳食
fiber it helps to normalize our stool
纤维来解决，它有助于使我们的粪便恢复正常，达到
bring it back to the middle so in a
中间状态。
perfect world where do we want to be we
理想情况下，我们
want to generally be pooping about once
希望每天排便一次，也就是
a day so you want your gut Transit time
肠道传输时间
to be about 24 hours or
在24小时或更短。也就是说，
unhealthy if it takes two days for this
如果一个人需要两天才能排便，这是否就意味着不健康呢？ 如果这种情况
to show up in their poo no I wouldn't
出现在它们的粪便中，我不会
characterize them as being unhealthy but
说它们不健康，但
I I do think like this is one of the
我认为这是
things that we can look at that's simple
我们可以观察的迹象之一。 很简单，
it's it's nearly free and um available
几乎免费，而且
all of us to try at home so yeah so you
我们所有人都可以在家尝试。所以，你
you you would assert that if someone's
会说，如果有人一天
going to the toilet you know three or
上厕所三
four times a day or more then there's
四次甚至更多，那很
probably a fiber problem there's May
可能是膳食纤维摄入不足的问题。
well be a fiber problem and if they're
如果他们长期便秘，那也可能是膳食纤维摄入不足导致的。
problem at the heart of it generally
总的来说，是的。
speaking yes now I will say that fiber
不过，我要说的是，膳食纤维的问题
is not as simple as I wish that it was
并不像我希望的那样简单。我之所以提到
and and the reason why I bring that up
这一点，
is that for a person who's low on their
是因为对于膳食纤维摄入量低的人来说，
issues increasing fiber is hard for
增加膳食纤维的摄入量很困难，他们可能会因此出现这些问题。
them and many people don't feel well if
很多人如果排便太用力太快，会感觉不舒服，比如身体会蜷缩起来，
this it folds them over they feel unwell
感觉很不舒服。
I was in the exact same spot 10 years
十年
ago if I tried to eat like you know
前我也是这样，如果我尝试吃
chili with a bunch of beans
辣椒和很多豆子，
I was not happy so I prefer to stay away
我会感觉很不舒服，所以我更喜欢避免吃这些。
from that so the point that I'm trying
所以我想
to make about this the reason why people
表达的观点是，人们
struggle with fiber is because we are
难以摄入膳食纤维的原因是……
100% reliant on our gut microbes to
我们100%依赖肠道微生物来
digest our fiber for us we don't have
消化纤维，我们自身没有
the enzymes to break them down to break
分解
down fiber the gut microbes are doing it
纤维的酶，肠道微生物负责这项工作。
so if you have a damaged microbiome and
所以，如果你的肠道菌群受损，而且
you never eat fiber you're you can't
你从不摄入纤维，就不能
expect your microbes to be good at
指望你的微生物能很好地
digesting fiber are microbes they learn
消化纤维。微生物会学习，
and they get good at the stuff that we
它们会擅长我们
allow them to practice so when we start
允许它们练习的东西。因此，当我们开始
to add more fiber the way that I
增加纤维摄入量时，我
recommends that people do this is to
建议大家从小剂量
start low and go slow that just means
开始，慢慢增加，这意味着每次只
adding a little bit at a time slowly
添加一点点，
over over the course of at least weeks
至少持续几周甚至
if not months um and this is what allows
几个月。这样可以让
your your gut microbes basically to keep
你的肠道微生物逐渐
up and adjust to what you're doing what
适应你的饮食。那么
about fecal treatment you said there
粪便疗法呢？你刚才提到，
that if our gut microbiome is damaged um
如果我们的肠道菌群受损，
it's not going to be great processing
它就无法很好地处理
the fiber so can't I just get someone's
纤维。那么，我能不能弄一些粪便中微生物含量高达
poop who has you know that 60% of their
60%的人的粪便
poop is the the microbes and eat it or
来吃，或者
do some kind of feal treatment where I
进行某种粪便疗法，比如把粪便喂给
put it in my body so this is this is
我的肠道微生物？ 所以，
actually being done um now we've been
目前我们已经
doing feal transplants where we would
开展了粪便移植，也就是
take from a
从
donor and put it into a person for an
捐赠者身上取出粪便，移植到
infection called C diff and we've been
感染艰难梭菌（C. diff）的患者体内。这项技术已经
doing this for more than 10 years
应用超过十年了。
and it is fascinating the studies with
有趣的是，
fot transplant in humans have not
粪便移植在人体上的研究并没有像治疗艰难梭菌感染那样
been uh as successful as they were for
成功。
diff so we would love to say that we
我们很希望
could treat ulcer of
能够用粪便移植治疗溃疡性
colitis which is inflammatory bowel
结肠炎（一种炎症性肠病），但就
cannot at least where we stand today but
目前而言，似乎还无法做到。不过，
there is something interesting that we
我们
found in one of the studies on this
在一项相关研究中发现了一些有趣的现象。
where again these studies are small like
这项研究规模较小，
we need bigger studies to really fully
我们需要更大规模的研究才能真正全面地
understand this there was one study
了解它。其中一项研究纳入了
where they did have a couple of people
几位患有
on with all sort of cus who went into
各种溃疡性结肠炎的患者，他们在接受
no longer active after a feal transplant
粪便移植后病情缓解，这意味着他们的疾病不再活跃。研究人员
and they asked the question what was
探究了这些患者的
unique and they found they all had the
独特之处，发现他们都来自
same
同一位
donor so what we think is that there's
捐赠者。因此，我们认为，
probably specific donors for specific
可能存在针对特定疾病的特定捐赠者，这些捐赠者或许
diseases that could actually potentially
能够真正
fix those issues because at their root
解决这些问题，因为这些疾病的根源在于
they are gut issues I think that the
肠道。 我认为
future of feal transplant is very
粪便移植的未来前景非常
promising but the complexity of figuring
光明，但问题在于如何
out who are these donors like could I be
确定合适的捐赠者，比如我是否
a good donor for some specific disease
适合捐赠给某种
that I don't even have myself and don't
我自身没有、也一无所知的特定疾病。
know anything about possibly and this is
这就是
what we have to figure out and how do
我们必须解决的问题。
these poop transplants happen is it
粪便移植是如何进行的？是
orally or is it some other way are they
口服还是其他方式？是注射
injecting this poop are they putting up
粪便，还是塞进
their butt what are they doing with it
肛门？他们用什么方法？
there's a couple ways so the classic is
有几种方法，最经典的
a colonoscopy so the way that I always I
方法是结肠镜检查。我通常的做法
would always administer it is that the
是，
patient comes in for a colonoscopy
患者来做结肠镜检查，
they're completely asleep they're not
他们完全处于麻醉状态，对
aware of anything that's happening and
发生的一切都毫无察觉。
during the procedure I basically release
在检查过程中，我会把
this stuff it's a liquid it's not as
这种液体（听起来很恶心，但其实没那么恶心）注入肛门。
butt the colonoscopy yeah
结肠镜检查……是的，
up the butt yeah let Tobe up the butt
塞进肛门。是的，塞进肛门。
now the new technology that's been
近年来出现的新技术
emerging in the last few years is that
是
they can actually dry out the stool so
可以将粪便干燥，
they liliz it and put it into capsules
然后装入胶囊。
you have to take a ton of capsules in
你需要服用很多。
order to do this but this is an
为了达到这个目的，需要服用胶囊，但这是一种
alternative choice is like you could
替代方案，比如你可以
start taking this what I think would be
开始服用这个，我觉得会很
interesting
有趣。胶囊
breaks well hopefully not do you know
破裂？希望不会，你知道
what I mean I've had a couple omega
我的意思吗？我之前有几个
omega 3 capsules break and it's a
欧米伽-3胶囊破裂了，那简直是噩梦。
nightmare so oh dear imagine trying to
天哪，想象一下
get that sh on my te we want to
要把那些粪便弄到我的……我们想要……
be um what what we're transitioning
嗯，我们正在向什么方向过渡？
towards like the past was this big event
过去，这需要做一件大事，比如
colonoscopy well to do that repeatedly
结肠镜检查。反复做这种检查
is simply not sustainable that's not
根本不可持续，也不
realistic now what we're entering into
现实。现在，我们正在进入一个新阶段，
is the possibility that you could do
你可以
this every day you could just take your
每天都服用，你可以
poop capsule every single day God love
每天都服用粪便胶囊。上帝啊，我真想
to be the CEO of that company that' be
成为这家公司的CEO，那该
so fun I mean I think that I think that
多有趣啊！我的意思是，我认为
this is going to happen we just need
这将会发生，我们只需要……是的，
really yeah but I think we need the the
但我认为我们需要
technology is there the technology is
技术。技术已经存在了，
there so what do we need we need to
那么我们需要什么？我们需要找到
identify who are the proper donors for
合适的捐赠者，
this and we need to run the clinical
我们需要进行临床
trials to prove that it will work but to
试验来证明它的有效性。但对
me this is a super probiotic because
我来说，这是一种超级益生菌，因为
it's not just you know most probotics
它不仅仅是…… 大多数益生菌都
are just one single strain um and they
只是单一菌株，它们
can be beneficial I'm not disparaging
可能对人体有益。我绝无贬低
probotics in any way they can definitely
益生菌的意思，它们当然
be beneficial but what we're talking
有益。但我们现在讨论的
about is a new future where you're
是一个全新的未来，在这个未来里，人们
actually reconstituting a healthy
实际上是在重建一个健康的
microbiome and Stephen on this topic
微生物群。斯蒂芬，关于这个话题，我简单说一下，
real quick it is fascinating because
它非常引人入胜，因为
some of the people who are in this
一些从事这个
space they're worried about the way the
领域的人担心世界
microbes right so there's been this
微生物群的现状。
concept that perhaps you've heard about
你可能听说过这样一个概念：一场
this great uh Extinction event that's
大规模的物种灭绝事件正在
taking place right where many species of
发生，许多
animals are dying and um and they're
动物物种正在死亡，它们
gone microbials scientists are worried
消失了。微生物科学家们很担心，
cuz the same thing is happening on a
因为同样的事情也发生在
microbial level so if you were to
微生物层面。如果我们把
compare our microbiome as westerners to
西方人的微生物群和
a person who lives in a more uh
生活
primitive environment in Africa we have
在非洲更原始环境中的人的微生物群进行比较，我们拥有的
half the microbes that they
微生物数量只有他们的一半。
do and so what these scientists are
所以这些科学家们正在思考：
people what if we need them what if we
如果我们需要那些在非洲原始环境中发现的微生物呢？如果我们
evolved and they're required for us so
进化而来，它们会怎么样？ 对我们来说，这是必要的。所以
so they're creating a bank where they're
他们正在建立一个“粪便银行”，
collecting these poop samples from like
收集
uh primitive tribal people and saving
原始部落居民的粪便样本并保存起来，以防万一
the only way
唯一的办法
back is to actually take the poop from
就是提取
these people and create super probiotics
这些人的粪便，制造超级益生菌来
that would help to reconstitute our
帮助重建我们的
microbiome I'm so compelled by this idea
微生物群。我非常着迷于这个想法，
supplements in the future that are just
未来可能会出现一系列
like poop capsules I don't think it'll
类似粪便胶囊的补充剂。不过，
be supplements though I think it'll be
我认为它不会是补充剂，而是会受到
completely regulated well what I mean by
严格的监管。我的意思是，
regulation between supplements and um
补充剂和
Pharmaceuticals and I don't think
药品在监管方面是有区别的。我认为
they'll have any choice but to regulate
他们别无选择，只能像监管药品
this on the same level that you would a
一样监管它。
drug because in my head I have this idea
因为在我看来，
of you know if this really takes off
如果这项技术真的流行起来，拥有
people with great poop are going to be
优质粪便的人将会非常
you know expensive dude I think my stock
昂贵。老兄，我觉得我的身价
is rising to be honest with you want
正在上涨。说实话，如果你想要
some of your poop all right if you want
一些你的粪便，好吧，如果你想要
my poop you will have to pay for it but
我的粪便，你就得付费，但
it's going to be expensive if you only
如果你只
go to because you're healthy you go to
去…… 因为你健康，
the toilet once a day it's going to be
每天只上一次厕所，所以它就像
like gold
黄金一样珍贵。
um and that's the fascinating thing poop
嗯，这就是粪便如今最令人着迷的地方——它正经历着
history of comebacks right now maybe
史上最强劲的复兴。也许
maybe that's where we live in a post AI
这就是我们生活在后人工智能
World maybe that's the currency we trade
时代的未来，也许这就是我们交易的货币。
in you know what I'm saying because
你知道我的意思吗？因为
we're gonna have little else to do so I
我们可能没什么其他事可做了。所以，
you know gosh that is a dark uh
你知道，这真是一个黑暗、
disturbing vision for the future but I
令人不安的未来景象，但我
could see where I could see where that's
能理解它的
possible I mean I I do think like it's
可能性。我的意思是，
fascinating to consider that what what
想想
we once disparaged as completely
曾经被我们贬低为
worthless has turned into the powerful
毫无价值的东西，如今却变成了
treatment that doctors are administering
医生
in the hospital to treat the uncurable
在医院里用来治疗不治之症的强效疗法，
infection and now is the future of
而且还是科学的未来，这真是
science it's going to be so interesting
太有趣了。它甚至可能
could like you know change the class
改变
system in the country that you know like
国家的阶级制度，比如
upper class could just be people with
上层阶级可能就是拥有
the best poop and then lower classes if
最优质粪便的人，而下层阶级，如果
you've got like a really narrow gut
你肠道菌群非常单一，
microbiome and your poop is useless you
你的粪便毫无用处，你就
can't sell it to anybody well it's kind
卖不出去。这真是太令人
of fascinating that you say that because
着迷了。 你说
the issue is that if you look at the
这话是因为，如果你观察那些
developed than the US and the UK um you
比美国和英国欠发达国家的微生物群，你会发现，他们经济条件
know they they they have less money
较差，所以饮食比较简单，
eat a more basic diet which often is
通常以
based upon whole grains and legumes
全谷物和豆类为主。豆类
beans and rice is like the essential
和米饭是基本食物，但
diet yet these things are actually so
这些食物实际上
good for our gut microbes like to me
对我们的肠道微生物非常有益。在我看来，
legumes are the least talked about food
豆类是最不常被提及的食物，但
that we should be talking about because
我们应该多多谈论它们，因为
they're high in fiber they're high in
它们富含纤维、
resistant starches and polyphenols all
抗性淀粉和多酚，这些都是
of which are prebiotics and this is why
益生元。这就是为什么
when people eat more beans they live
人们多吃豆类，寿命更长，
longer with less disease so it's kind of
患病更少。这很
interesting cuz like popper food cheap
有意思，因为那些廉价的、价格低廉的
food is the food actually that is the
食物实际上才是
best for us because it feeds these
对我们最好的，因为它们能滋养这些
microbes lazy westerners are going to
微生物。懒惰的西方人又要
get on a boat like they did Once Upon a
像《殖民者》里那样，乘船去非洲掠夺
incredible you know they the the gold
黄金、
and the Diamonds and whatever else they
钻石和其他
it's claimed that they stole from Africa
据称是他们偷来的东西，
and they're going to get back on that
然后他们又要回到那艘船上了。
boat and go over there and start
然后去那里
stealing poop I think that that I could
偷粪便，我觉得
definitely see that happening there has
这完全有可能发生。事实上，
actually been fights over when they they
当他们
discover um uh prehistoric poop like
发现史前粪便，比如
fossilized poop there's fights over who
化石粪便时，就会发生争夺战，争夺
gets to control that because if you
控制权。
think about it's like Jurassic Park
想想《侏罗纪公园》开头，琥珀里有
there's that Amber with the mosquito and
蚊子，
the needle goes in you extract the DNA
针头扎进去提取DNA。
what if we could extract the DNA from
如果我们能从史前粪便中提取DNA
prehistoric poop and study that and
并进行研究，甚至
potentially use
可能利用这些
that the poop studies that have been
研究成果呢？粪便研究
done really compelled by them because I
确实很受关注，因为我
hear that there's been a lot of sort of
听说已经有很多
poop transplant studies done in in mice
粪便移植实验在小鼠身上进行。
as well yeah and what what what are we
是的，我们
seeing from those studies right okay so
从这些研究中看到了什么？好的，
we were talking about these different um
我们刚才在讨论与微生物
conditions that are connected back to
相关的各种疾病。
that we prove this of course we want
当然，证明这一点的方法之一是进行
human research but part of building uh
人体研究，但构建
our argument and and filling in the
论点、填补
pieces of the puzzle is like Mouse
空白的方法之一是进行小鼠
research and these mice there it's we
研究。这些小鼠我们
have complete control and they're much
完全可以控制。 它们
more simple to manipulate and so we have
更容易操作，所以我们有
the ability to do a fecal transplant
能力进行粪便移植，
even potentially from a human
甚至可以把人的粪便移植
to a mouse and then see what happens and
到小鼠身上，然后观察会发生什么。
so let me take you through a couple of
接下来，我将带大家看看
examples of what we have seen in
我们在
clinical studies and I'm more than happy
临床研究中观察到的一些例子，我很乐意向
to point people towards the studies that
大家推荐
I'm referring to um classic study they
我提到的研究。一项经典的研究
took identical human twins so again we
选取了同卵双胞胎，我们在本
of the of the episode identical human
集开头也讨论过这一点。同卵双胞胎拥有相同的
code and in this case one was obese and
基因，其中一个肥胖，
one is
另一个
thin and they have a different
瘦弱，他们的
microbiome
肠道菌群不同。
and when you transfer human poop into
当你把人类粪便移植到
mice you also transfer the body
小鼠体内时，
type even when you feed the mice the
即使喂食
exact same food the exact same number of
完全相同的食物和
calories so we hear about this calories
卡路里，你也会把体型移植到小鼠体内。我们经常听到“摄入卡路里-消耗卡路里”的
in calories out concept which by the way
概念，
we could talk about if you want to but
如果你想的话，我们可以讨论一下，但这个概念
it's not perfectly true and this is
并不完全正确。这
showing you the complexity that exists
说明了
your microbiome impacts how you work
肠道菌群的复杂性，它会影响你如何利用
with those calories the mouse that uh
这些卡路里。
receives the obese microbiome it's like
接受肥胖小鼠肠道菌群的小鼠就像逆流而
calories and then the thin mouse mouse
上，肠道菌群会改变小鼠吸收所有卡路里的方式。 瘦小鼠就像顺着
um it's like swimming with the current
水流游泳一样，
at your back it's a lot easier you
更容易保持体型。即使
consume the same number of calories you
摄入相同的卡路里，也
don't gain any weight that's just
不会增加体重，这完全是
metabolism by the way we have studies
新陈代谢的功劳。顺便一提，我们也有研究表明
also diabetes can be transferred we have
糖尿病是可以转移的。
studies in humans
在人体研究中，
where you can actually do a feal
我们可以将健康
transplants from a person who does not
人的粪便移植
have diabetes to a person who does have
到
diabetes and their blood sugar measures
糖尿病患者身上，患者的血糖水平
will
会得到
improve in
改善。在
humans we have uh immune studies you can
免疫学研究中，我们可以将
take a person who has all sort of cidus
患有各种疾病（
which we were talking about a moment ago
我们刚才提到过）的人的
and transfer their poop into a mouse and
粪便移植到小鼠体内，小鼠
that Mouse will have all sort of
也会表现出相应的
cidus we have uh mood studies uh where
疾病。在情绪学研究中，
you could take a human who has anxiety
我们可以将患有焦虑症、抑郁症或创伤后应激障碍（
PTSD and transfer their poop into a
PTSD）的人的粪便移植到
mouse and the mouse receives the mood
小鼠体内，小鼠也会表现出相应的情绪
phenotype so basically like again this
表型。所以，这方面还
uh needs to be studied more in humans we
需要在人体中进行更多研究，因为人体情况
are more complicated you can't just cure
更复杂，目前还不能通过人与人之间的
diseases like this by transferring poop
粪便移植来治愈这类疾病。
yet but when it comes to mice where they
但在小鼠这种相对
are less complicated it's very clear
简单的动物身上，
that the microbiome plays a central role
微生物群
in these conditions because you can
在这些疾病中发挥着核心作用这一点已经非常明确了。 因为你可以
transfer the condition using human poop
用人类粪便来转移这种状况，
and take me on a journey of what that
然后带我了解一下
poop's doing so I I get the skinny poop
粪便的作用。比如，我
from a skinny twin and I put it into a
从一个瘦双胞胎身上取下瘦的粪便，放到一只
mouse the mouse gets skinny or I get the
小鼠体内，小鼠就变瘦了；或者我
obese twin I take the obese twins poop
取一个肥胖双胞胎的粪便，
and I put it into a mouse the mouse gets
放到一只小鼠体内，小鼠就
obese what's going on in that mice's
变胖了。那么，这只小鼠体内发生了什么让它
body to make it obese I'm I'm assuming
变胖呢？我猜想，
it's basically picking up some of the
它基本上是吸收了一些
microbes which are impacting the gut
微生物，这些微生物会影响肠道
microbiome which is creating a
菌群，产生一种
postbiotic compound which is influencing
后生元化合物，从而影响
its metabolism or something something
其新陈代谢等等。
like that you could eat the so if you
如果你的
have a microbiome designed to produce
肠道菌群能够产生
short chain fatty acids you and I could
短链脂肪酸，你和我
eat the exact same meal but the person
吃同样的饭菜，但
who has the microbiome designed to
肠道菌群能够
create short chain fatty acids will get
产生短链脂肪酸的人会摄入
more short chain fatty acids and the and
更多的短链脂肪酸。其
the product of this is that those short
结果是，这些短
chain fatty acids now will have effects
链脂肪酸会对
throughout the entire body including
全身产生影响，包括
affecting our metabolism and affecting
影响新陈代谢、影响
our blood sugar affecting our insulin
血糖、影响胰岛素
sensitivity infecting our blood lipids
敏感性、影响
after a meal affecting fat storage
餐后血脂、影响脂肪储存，
whether or not you turn on fat storage
无论你是否…… 关于脂肪储存，
or whether you turn off fat storage and
或者说是关闭脂肪储存、
turn on fat burning it really does shine
开启脂肪燃烧，这确实与“摄入
alert on this calories in calories out
卡路里-消耗卡路里”的概念密切相关。
thing because yeah I mean there's so
因为，
many people I've talked about this a few
我之前也多次提到过，很多人
times that just think you just have to
认为只要
eat below the required amount amount of
摄入的
calories for your body and you'll lose
卡路里低于身体所需，就能
weight but in that example it proves
减肥。但这个例子证明，还有
that there's this other process going on
其他过程在进行，
that's going to determine I guess is it
它决定了——我猜是有
how many of those calories go through or
多少卡路里被消耗掉，还是
is it just how your body processes that
你的身体如何处理这些
energy part of it is part of it is
能量？一部分是生热作用，也就是
thermogenesis meaning fat burning yeah
脂肪燃烧。
part of it is also what you poop out
一部分也与你的排泄物有关。
okay they've actually found that people
他们发现，
who have a healthier microbiome they
肠道菌群更健康的人，
poop out more calories ah okay
排泄的卡路里更多。哦，这很
interesting what do you think of the
有意思。你觉得“摄入
calories and calor out thing if someone
卡路里-消耗卡路里”这个概念怎么样？如果有人
comes to you and they say I want to lose
来找你，说“我想减肥，
Doc and they say I've had this calories
医生”，而你的
in calories out thing is the answer so
答案是“摄入卡路里-消耗卡路里”，所以
I'm just eating less I'm eating lots of
我吃得少了，我吃了很多
pizza but I'm just having less calories
披萨，但卡路里摄入量减少了。
I don't I don't like that obviously so
显然，我不喜欢这样。所以对
to me dietary quality is the key um
我来说，饮食质量才是关键。 关键在于，
there's too many examples where dietary
有太多例子表明饮食
quality so first of all our weight is
质量至关重要。首先，我们的体重
our our health is not entirely
并非完全
determined by our
由健康决定，它当然是
weight is it a major factor yes it is
一个重要因素，
but there's so much more M so so dietary
但还有更多因素。一项又一项的
quality study after study after study
研究
shows us that dietary quality is crucial
表明，饮食质量对
to the health of our microbiome and also
我们的肠道菌群健康、
to our Global Health our longevity and
整体健康、寿命以及
our risk for disease so to pretend that
患病风险都至关重要。因此，假装饮食质量
that doesn't matter would be completely
无关紧要是完全
false and
错误和不
inaccurate um the idea that calories is
准确的。至于认为卡路里是
the only thing that matters what I do
唯一重要因素的观点，我
want to say is this there is some truth
想说的是，卡路里确实很重要，
there's absolutely some truth to this if
如果
you reduce your caloric take you will
你减少卡路里摄入，
lose weight the problem is that your
体重会减轻。问题在于，你的
body will compensate by slowing down
身体会通过减慢
your metabolism and so then it puts you
新陈代谢来补偿，这会让你陷入一种困境，
in a in a predicament where you can't
你无法
continue to do this it's not sustainable
继续这样做，
because that weight loss eventually will
因为体重最终会
stop and then you will uh your appetite
停止下降，然后你的食欲会变得异常旺盛，
signals will grow so much that you will
你会
start to overeat and then when you
开始暴饮暴食。而当你
overeat not only do you gain the weight
暴饮暴食时，不仅体重会反弹，还会出现恶性循环。
fat they lose muscle mass like all
就像溜溜球一样，你的体重会反弹，甚至超过你之前的水平，哇！但问题在于，人们减肥时，燃烧的不仅仅是脂肪，还会损失肌肉。几乎所有的
weight loss is associated with a loss of
减肥过程都伴随着
muscle mass when you gain the weight
肌肉的流失。当你体重反弹时，
back the muscle doesn't come back you're
肌肉不会再回来，只会
just getting fat so so the issue is you
增加脂肪。所以
end up less healthy than when you
最终，你的健康状况会比减肥前更差。
started to me what I want is I want
我想要的是，
people to eat a diet where they can eat
人们可以自由地想吃多少就吃多少，
until they are
直到
full and still achieve their weight
吃饱为止，同时还能达到他们的体重
goals
目标。
and this is completely possible by
这完全可以通过
consuming a diet that's high in
食用富含
prebiotics because we hear so much about
益生元的食物来实现。我们经常听到
uh OIC or wovi um which is seml
OIC（或WOVI），也就是
semaglutide we hear so much about this
Semaglutide（司美格鲁肽），它是一种GLP-1受体激动剂。GLP-
and it's a glp1 Agonist gp1 is a gut
1是一种
hormone that exists within our body and
存在于我们体内的肠道激素，它
uh it makes us feel
能让我们产生
full we can stimulate GL lp1 through our
饱腹感。我们可以通过饮食来刺激GLP-1的分泌。
choices if you eat the right food which
如果你吃对了食物，也
is basically a high Prebiotic diet you
就是富含益生元的食物，你就能激活GLP-1，
naturally feel full and the result of
自然而然地产生饱腹感。
this is that in the process of actually
这样做的结果是…… 实际上，
activating your normal satiety signals
激活你正常的饱腹信号的过程
you will consume less calories satiety
会让你摄入更少的卡路里。饱腹
signals are basically hunger signals
信号本质上就是
hunger signals so basically yeah so the
饥饿信号。所以，
issue that we all have is that we eat an
我们面临的问题是，我们吃的是超
ultr processed diet an ultra Ultra
加工食品。首先，超
processed diet number one makes us
加工食品会让我们
ravenous right like We Can't Stop we
食欲大增，根本停不下来。
want it so bad number two it doesn't
其次，它无法
activate those fullness signals and so
激活饱腹信号。
the result is when we eat an ultra
结果就是，当我们吃超
processed diet we overeat and then you
加工食品时，我们会吃得过多，然后
feel like trash you feel like trash for
感觉很糟糕，这种糟糕的感觉会持续
a couple of hours and that is the result
几个小时。这就是吃得
of you overeating you've thrown yourself
过多的后果，它破坏了你的
metabolically out of balance right don't
新陈代谢平衡。
we all love the meal that tastes great
我们都喜欢那种美味可口，
but you eat until you're full and you
但吃到饱就停下来，然后
stop and actually feel energized and
感觉精力充沛，
don't need to take a nap or drink an
不需要小睡或喝
energy drink to compensate for what you
能量饮料来弥补
just did and that happens when we do
刚刚摄入的能量。当我们用传统的
this the the oldfashioned way by
方式进食时，就会出现这种情况。所谓传统的方式，
oldfashioned I mean like prior to modern
指的是在现代
history when ultra-processed Foods came
社会超加工食品出现之前。
into uh existence if we go back to the
如果我们回到
old way of eating you would simply eat
过去的饮食方式，你会吃到……
until you activate these hormones things
激活这些激素，
like glp1 which you know is concentrated
比如GLP-1（你知道，
in this drug or peptide YY these are gut
这种药物中浓度很高）或肽YY，这些都是肠道
hormones that basically tell our body
激素，它们基本上告诉我们的身体
when to stop eating everyone's going
何时停止进食。每个人都在
crazy about a zmek I keep hearing about
疯狂地谈论ZMEK，我一直听到这种
this drug I think Elon Musk recently
药。我想埃隆·马斯克最近
said he had had it and I know a few
说他服用过，我还认识一些
other people that have um started taking
其他人也开始服用
a Zac there I would say you know then
ZMEK。我想说的是，
none of them are overweight necessarily
他们不一定超重，
yeah um but they're doing it because
但他们服用是因为
it's now been framed as kind of super
它现在被宣传成一种超级
drug yeah which can help you drop weight
药物，可以
super quickly by making you feel
通过让你产生饱腹感来帮助你快速减肥。
satiated yeah what do you think of his
你觉得他的
MC well I come back to this so first of
MC怎么样？嗯，我再回到这个问题。首先，
all let me say that for people who need
我想说，对于需要它的人来说，
it it's I'm glad it's there um I don't
我很高兴它存在。我不
think that the entire world needs OIC in
认为全世界都需要服用阿片类药物
order to be healthy is there any side
才能保持健康。它有什么
effects or
副作用吗？
100% 100% first of all digestive
首先，消化系统
symptoms um massive uh massively common
症状，非常常见，而且非常普遍。此外，它还有
long-term risks and many of which we
长期风险，其中许多风险我们
don't simply know much about because
知之甚少。 因为
people haven't been using the drug long
人们使用这种药物的时间还不够长，
enough for us to really fully understand
我们无法真正完全了解
what happens if you use because once you
一旦开始使用会发生什么。
if you stop you gain all the weight back
如果你停止服用，体重就会反弹。
so once you start using it you're
所以一旦你开始服用，
basically committing to however old you
基本上就意味着你要一直坚持下去，无论
years on years if you know decades um we
你多大年纪，你都要这样做很多年，甚至几十年。我们
don't know what happens after a couple
不知道几年后会发生什么，
gut microbiome taking a zek yeah I think
服用Zek是不是跳过了肠道菌群发育过程中的一个步骤？是的，我认为
that's the point is that if we so you
关键就在这里。如果
know if we look at our countries the US
我们看看美国
and the UK um there's a major fiber
和英国，就会发现那里普遍存在严重的膳食纤维
deficiency and I don't think you know I
缺乏问题。我知道
realize I'm out there pounding the drum
我一直在强调
on this but I don't think this is talked
这一点，但我认为人们对膳食纤维的讨论还不够
about enough perhaps because people
多，也许是因为人们
don't think that fiber is
觉得膳食纤维不够
sexy but I think fiber is sexy because
吸引人。但我认为膳食纤维很吸引人，因为
it's so crucial and important to our to
它对我们的
our health and this is an example where
健康至关重要。这是一个
this is 100% true so uh 95% of Americans
百分之百正确的例子：95%的美国人
are deficient in fiber the average woman
膳食纤维摄入不足，美国女性平均
is getting 15 grams of fiber per day
每天只摄入15克膳食纤维，而
she's supposed to be getting at least 25
她们应该至少摄入25克。
in the US the average man is getting 18
这个人每天只摄入18
grams of fiber per day he's supposed to
克纤维，而他应该
be getting 38 that's a massive massive
摄入38克，这严重
deficiency and the issue is that the
不足。问题在于，
fiber is what actually empowers the gut
纤维实际上能够增强肠道
microbes by the way through short chain
微生物的功能。顺便说一句，
fatty acids the fiber is what empowers
纤维
the gut microbes through short chain
通过短链脂肪酸促进肠道微生物
fatty acids to release these gut
释放肠道
hormones like gop1 and peptide y y so my
激素，例如GOP-1和肽YY。所以我的
thing is this because again like our
想法是，因为我们的
health is not determined exclusively by
健康并非完全取决于
our weight balance there are other
体重，还有其他
things other than that why don't we cons
因素。为什么我们不
try consuming these Foods the average
尝试多吃这些食物呢？
American is 10% of their calories from
美国人平均只有10%的卡路里来自
Plants fiber containing food what if we
富含纤维的植物性食物。如果我们
could make that 30% or 50% I think that
能把这个比例提高到30%甚至50%呢？我认为
we would see a massive difference there
我们会看到巨大的变化。有
was a study that was done it's one of my
一项研究，是我最
favorite studies of all time by uh uh
喜欢的研究之一，由
professor in New Zealand his name is
新西兰的
Andrew Reynolds and he compiled all the
安德鲁·雷诺兹教授完成的。他收集了所有关于
available data on fiber what happens
纤维的现有数据，研究了
when people consume more fiber here's
人们摄入更多纤维后会发生什么。结果如下：
happens they lose
他们会
weight uh they are less likely to have a
减肥，心脏病发作的风险降低，
heart attack they're less likely to die
死于心脏病的风险也降低。
of heart disease
心脏病患者
they're less likely to have a stroke
患中风的几率会降低，
diabetes they're less likely to be
糖尿病患者患
diagnosed with multiple different types
多种
of cancer they're less likely to die of
癌症的几率也会降低，死于
cancer um their blood pressure goes down
癌症的几率也会降低。他们的血压会下降，
their blood sugar control improves their
血糖控制会改善，
cholesterol goes down okay like that's
胆固醇也会降低。这些好处就
sitting there for us available all we
摆在那里，唾手可得。我们只
have to do is make the dietary changes
需要改变饮食习惯。
and again what happens in that process
在这个过程中，
is you consume more fiber it comes in
你会摄入更多纤维，纤维会
the contact with your gut microbes they
与肠道微生物接触，
release short chain fatty acids and they
释放短链脂肪酸，从而对
entire body so to me I agree with you I
全身产生修复作用。所以，我同意你的观点，我
think that we're missing this um this
认为我们忽略了这关键的
middle piece and when we're reaching for
中间环节。当我们选择服用
something that's an expensive drug it's
昂贵的药物时，这些
something that's an expensive drug and
药物不仅价格昂贵，而且
it has a very real risk of side effects
副作用的风险也很大，因为
we just don't know what happens after
我们根本不知道服用几年后会发生什么。
you take it for a couple of years um I I
我
don't understand why we would do that
不明白，既然
listed by simply increasing your fiber
增加纤维
intake I have so many conversations with
摄入量就能带来这么多好处，为什么我们还要服用这些药物呢？我和
my friends about various drugs that
朋友们经常讨论各种药物。 他们说
they're taking performance drugs mfil
他们在服用兴奋剂，比如Mfil、
Zenex Etc and when I speak to them they
Zenex等等。当我跟他们谈起这些药的时候，
they're very passionate that there's no
他们非常热情地声称这些药没有任何
side effects on all all of these sort of
副作用，而
things that I
我
consider cheating yeah and I and I have
认为这些药就是作弊。是的，我
to Cave at this because there are some
不得不承认，确实有一些患有
diabetes or other cardiovascular issues
糖尿病或其他心血管疾病的人，服用
some of these drugs
这些药可以挽救他们的生命。
yeah but for the most part the people
但是，据
that I know that are consuming these
我所知，大多数服用这些
drugs aren't doing it for that reason
药的人并非出于这个原因，而是为了
they're doing it for vanity reasons or
虚荣心或
for performance reasons where it's like
为了提高成绩，就像
taking a shortcut and every shortcut I
走捷径一样。我
believe in life comes with a cost yeah
相信，人生中的每一条捷径都是要付出代价的。是的，
you're talking like a doctor you're
你说话就像个
talking like a doctor because basically
医生，因为
what you're talking about is risk versus
你说的其实就是风险
uh risk versus benefit and the way that
与收益的权衡。我
I think and every other doctor thinks
和其他医生一样，都会考虑
about their patient is does the benefit
收益是否
outweigh the risk but there is always
大于风险。但
always risk in association with these
这些药物总是伴随着风险。我与
most other doctors where I turn to the
其他医生最大的不同之处在于，
corner my career is when I started to
我开始
ask ask the question why are we waiting
质疑为什么我们要等到出现问题才采取行动。
until we get to the point that we need
我们需要
to write a prescription for a drug why
开药方，为什么
are we waiting until that point why are
非要等到那时才行动？为什么
we not intervening in a much earlier
不更早介入，
point where we could transform a
改变一个
person's life and get them to a place
人的生活，让他们永远
where they never actually get this
不会患上这种
disease or if they get this disease it's
疾病；或者即使患上了，
so much easier for us to control that
我们也更容易控制病情。所以，我最终想说的其实就是，
why would we why would we take a drug if
如果
we could change our diet and our
我们能改变饮食和
lifestyle and actually protect ourselves
生活方式来保护自己，为什么还要吃药呢？这岂不是更
it's easier it's much easier easier yeah
容易吗？
it is it is much easier there's no doubt
毫无疑问，这确实容易得多。
but the problem is you pay a price for
但问题是，这样做是有代价的，
that and the price is unobvious so
而且代价并不明显。所以，如果
you've got an easier option where the
有一种更简单的选择，好处显而易见，但成本和
benefits are clear and the cost the risk
风险却不
is unobvious
明显，
a logical human being would take that
一个理性的人如果负担得起，肯定会选择这
path if they can afford it I agree
条路。我同意，问题在于，
the issue is that these are not the same
这两种情况并不相同。
things though and what I mean by that is
我的意思是，
that um you have
假设你患有
diabetes okay HP like hypothetically I
糖尿病，好吧，HP，就像假设
hypothetically you have diabetes okay
你没有糖尿病一样，好吧，好吧，
cool we give you a drug for your
我们给你开药。 你的
diabetes um that drug covers up the
糖尿病，嗯，那种药掩盖了
issue I can get your blood sugar down
问题。我可以降低你的血糖，
but that's not fixing the problem I'm
但这并没有解决问题，我并
not actually fixing your diabetes right
没有真正治愈你的糖尿病，对吧？
so to me like we shouldn't equate um
所以我觉得我们不应该
taking a drug and like controlling a
把吃药和
disease on some level but truly what
在某种程度上控制疾病混为一谈，实际上
we're doing is we're just putting a
我们只是用药物掩盖了
sheet over the problems you don't see it
问题，你不再看到它了，对吧？
better outcomes long term are you
长期来看，这会带来更好的结果吗？你因为
your diabetes with a drug 100% yes no
用药控制糖尿病而更健康吗？100%是的，毫无
doubt but what if we could reverse your
疑问。但是如果我们能逆转你的
diabetes Diabetes Type 2 diab abetes
糖尿病呢？2型糖尿病，也就是
which is the uh uh kind that people
人们成年
acquire as an
后患上的那种糖尿病，
adult is highly reversible most people
是高度可逆的。大多数人
don't realize that like you don't need
没有意识到这一点。你不需要
to be drug dependent on di on Diabetes
依赖糖尿病
drugs in order to fix this issue take
药物来解决这个问题，
them when you need them but let's work
需要的时候就服用，但让我们从根本上解决问题。
on the root cause and by working on the
通过解决
root cause we can actually reverse the
根本原因，我们才能真正逆转
true problem and get you back to a place
问题，让你回到
where you don't need the drug at all but
完全不需要药物的状态。但这难道不需要
doesn't that require discipline and
自律、
willpower and
意志力和
motivation well I think I think it
动力吗？嗯， 我认为，这
requires understanding the path forward
需要理解前进的方向，
and making choices that are sustainable
并做出可持续的选择，
and that make you excited like I don't I
以及能让你感到兴奋的选择。就像我一样，我永远
would never ask a person to make choices
不会要求别人做出
that make them miserable I'm asking
让他们痛苦的选择。我要求
people to make choices that make them
人们做出让
feel great make them feel energized and
他们感觉良好、充满活力的选择，
yet at the same time actually are
同时这些选择也确实
contributing to Better Health so that
有助于改善健康，让
they can live longer with less disease
他们活得更久，减少疾病，
and be in a position that I want to be
并达到我所期望的状态——
in which is that I want to be in my 80s
我希望到了八十多岁还能像以前那样，
like dance with my grand kids so let's
和我的孙子孙女们一起跳舞。好了，我们来
close off on this subject of poop um my
结束关于粪便的话题吧。我的
team actually prepared some poop samples
团队之前准备了一些粪便样本，
earlier on because I was wondering as a
因为作为一名
gastroenterologist I wondered that if
肠胃科医生，我一直在想，是否
you could look at someone's poop and
可以通过观察一个人的粪便来
determine whether they have good gut
判断他们的肠道
health and if you can understand what's
健康状况，以及是否能仅凭粪便的形状就了解
going on in their body just by how their
他们身体的状况。
poop looks because poop comes in many
因为粪便的
shapes and sizes so what I have here is
形状和大小各不相同，所以我这里收集了
a variety of different shapes and sizes
各种不同形状和大小的
of poop yeah for anyone that can't see
粪便样本。是的，如果有人看不到，
will look at the screen if you're
可以看看屏幕，如果你正在
listening to this podcast on Spotify or
Spotify或YouTube上收听这个播客的话。
YouTube um different shapes and sizes of
嗯，这里有不同形状和大小的
poop here this is real human
粪便，这是真实的人类
poop so I'm going to pass you that so
粪便，我会把它递给你，
you can play around with it
你可以自己研究一下。是的，
yeah and why why does the shape and size
为什么粪便的形状和大小能
of our poop tell us anything why does it
告诉我们什么呢？为什么它很
matter and how is it indicating
重要？它如何反映出
something that's pertinent to our
与我们
overall health well because it goes back
整体健康相关的信息？这要回到
to what you mentioned earlier which is
你之前提到的，
our stool is actually microbial in
我们粪便重量的60%实际上来源于微生物。
origin so if you want a window into your
所以，如果你想了解你的
microbiome look at your poop you don't
微生物组，看看你的粪便就行了。你
necessarily need to go and do an
不一定需要去做
expensive test like quite simply looking
昂贵的检测，因为观察
at your poop is one of the ways that you
粪便本身就是了解你身体状况的方法之一。上世纪
study that was done in the 9s this a
90年代（很久以前了）有一项研究，研究对象不到
people exclusively in the City of
人，全部来自
Bristol and it led to the creation of a
布里斯托尔市。这项研究最终创建了一个
chart called the Bristol stool scale
名为“布里斯托尔粪便量表”的图表，
that here I'll put it on the screen yeah
我把它显示在屏幕上。是的，我们会一起了解一下，
through this but before we do I want to
但在那之前，我想
mention a few things real quick as the
快速提几件事。 作为
US medical director of Zoe I'm proud of
Zoe的美国医疗总监，我为自己
my contribution as a gastrologist as a
作为一名胃肠科
physician to the work that we're doing
医生对我们在美国开展的工作所做出的贡献感到自豪。
there and we not only did the blue poo
我们不仅进行了
study which we've talked about already
之前提到的“蓝色粪便研究”（即通过食用蓝色松饼来
and figure out your gut Transit time but
了解肠道传输时间），还开展了其他一些
we also did a couple of other things one
研究。其中一项
is called the Blue poo
是“蓝色粪便
challenge um where we had over 20,000
挑战”，我们邀请了全球超过2万名参与者
basically eating blue muffins and then
食用蓝色松饼，并向
reporting back to us on what was going
我们反馈他们的身体状况。
on with them and then more recently so
最近，
we recently did the largest study across
我们还在布里斯托尔市开展了一项研究，专门针对布里斯托尔市的2000名居民。此外，我们还在英国范围内开展了迄今为止规模最大的粪便研究，
movements so it was called the Big Pooh
名为“大便调查”（Big Pooh Review）。这项研究收集了
review and we had 142,000 people from
来自英国各地14.2万名参与者的
across the UK basically fill out a 17
17个
question survey and part of what we were
问题的调查问卷，其中一项研究内容
looking at was their Bristol stool form
是他们的布里斯托尔粪便形态，另一项研究内容是他们的
poop by the way the average person poops
排便频率。一般来说，普通人每天排便
1.7 times per day um and we're also
1.7次。 每天，嗯，我们还要
looking at like how it Associates with
看看它与
different conditions so as an example
不同疾病的关联。例如，
one in five people in the UK are
英国五分之一的人
constipated one in six people in the UK
便秘，六分之一的人
have diarrhea so it's interesting to
腹泻。所以
take a look at all these things so now
研究这些很有意思。现在
getting into the Bristol stool chart the
来看布里斯托大便分类图。
uh the dream that is real poop this is
嗯，理想的大便，这才是真正的大便，这
the it's lovely um this is the dream
很棒，嗯，这就是理想状态，
this is where we all want to be and this
这是我们都想达到的状态。这
is a Bristol 4 the Bristol 4 is the
是布里斯托4型。布里斯托4型是
classic uh where I come walking out of
经典状态，嗯，就像我
the bathroom in slow motion and rock
慢动作走出浴室，
music is jamming and doves are flying in
摇滚乐响起，鸽子
slow motion and I just I'm such a stud
慢动作飞翔，我简直太帅了。这是
so and that's after a Bristol four my
布里斯托4型之后的状态，我
wife knows what happens when I come out
老婆知道我出来的时候是什么样子，它
looking like that it's soft and formed
柔软成形，
okay and it's like a sausage or a
像香肠或
torpedo um so pretty smooth now um when
鱼雷，嗯，非常光滑。嗯，当
we move from a four to a three a three
我们从4型过渡到3型时，3型其实
is not that big of a deal but it is
没什么大不了的，但
getting some cracks and crevices in it
里面确实出现了一些裂缝和缝隙。
all right so and we're moving towards
所以，我们
constipation now a three you know uh a
现在正朝着便秘的方向发展，也就是3级。你知道，多摄入一些
little more fiber a little more
纤维，多
hydration some exercise these are simple
喝水，做一些运动，这些都是简单的
things that can help to get you back to
方法，可以帮助你恢复到
a four if you're having one of these a
4级（如果你是
three but that moves us to a Bristol 2
3级的话）。但这又让我们进入了布里斯托尔2级，这才是
where we are truly getting into
真正意义上的
constipation territory here and
便秘。
basically this is like if you took a
基本上，这就像你把
whole bunch of marbles of poop and
一大堆粪便弹珠塞
jammed them together so it still forms
在一起，它仍然能成形，
into something but it looks like a pack
但看起来像一包
of marbles of poop that are stuck
粘
together so that's a Bristol two stool
在一起的粪便弹珠。这就是布里斯托尔2级粪便，也
that's constipation and then finally a
就是便秘。最后，
Bristol one is when you're having the
布里斯托尔1级粪便是指你吃的是
rabbit the rabbit pellets and they're
兔粪，兔粪颗粒
hard they're not easy to get out and
很硬，不容易排出来，
sometimes they're a lot bigger than this
有时比这些小的粪便大得多。
this is these are small um so you would
这些粪便很小，所以你
you would form this up into what would
会把它们捏成
be like a golf
一个
ball and that golf ball would be uh like
高尔夫球大小的东西，这个高尔夫球大小的东西就是
a Bristol one okay all right you form it
布里斯托尔1级粪便。好的，你把它捏成
up into a hard ball like this um but
一个硬球，像这样，甚至可能
perhaps even bigger and it's actually
更大，而且实际上
hard for a person to pass this it's so
很难排出来。 把这个排出来，它
big it's so hard um that your bottom has
太大了，太硬了，嗯，你的肛门很难
uh a problem relaxing to let it out okay
放松，排不出来。好的，
so Bristol one and two are forms of
布里斯托尔1型和2型是
constipation let's go back to the middle
便秘的一种表现形式。我们回到中间，
we're going to start from five the the
从5型开始。
stool is soft it's not hard it's not
粪便很软，不硬，也不
lumpy bumpy it's soft but it's starting
结块，很软，但开始
to break into blobs different pieces of
分成小块。
poop um so and we're moving towards uh
嗯，
we're moving towards diarrhea where like
我们正朝着腹泻的方向发展，这时粪便中会残留一些
just like fragments of solid stool are a
固体碎片，这就是
Bristol six and then when it's just like
布里斯托尔6型。然后，当粪便完全呈液态时，
or the other thing a Bristol 6 could be
布里斯托尔6型也可能表现为
calie um where there's no form is just
卡利型，也就是没有形状，就像
someone popped down this formless Patty
有人拉出一块没有形状的饼状物。
and a Bristol 7 finally is straight
布里斯托尔7型最终表现为完全的
liquid straight liquid and how is this
液体，完全的液体。这和
pertinent to our gut microbiome our
我们的肠道菌群以及我们的
health what does this tell us about our
健康有什么关系呢？这告诉我们什么
health there's been now multiple studies
健康问题呢？现在已经有很多研究，
including our work at Zoe on the blue
包括我们在Zoe进行的关于蓝色
poop study uh that was published in the
粪便的研究，该研究发表在《
journal gut there's now been multiple
肠道》（Gut）杂志上。 多项
studies where basically what they found
研究发现，通过
is that if you could look at which of
观察
these Bristol types you have it does
你的布里斯托大便类型，我们可以
give us some insights into your gut
深入了解你的肠道
microbiome and what's happening there so
菌群及其健康状况。理想情况下，我们希望大便类型在
spectrum of three four or five we
3、4或5之间，最好是4型。3型或5型大便并不算
unhealthy if you have a three or a five
不健康。4型大便（有点像
of like a sausage it's kind of like a
香肠，质地
smooth sausage yeah is
光滑）是
optimal how does one do that what is
最佳状态。那么，如何才能排出4型大便呢？是什么因素促使人们排出
turning it into a type four what are
4型大便？
what are they eating doing yeah
人们的饮食习惯是什么？这是一个
interesting question we uh one of the
有趣的问题。
things that we found in the Big Pooh
我们在“大便
review which is our Nationwide survey of
调查”（一项覆盖全美
142,000 people we actually looked at
14.2万人的调查）中发现，
what they were eating and we were able
膳食
to find associations between fiber
纤维
intake and specifically plant-based food
摄入量，特别是植物性食物
intake and having a number four so in
摄入量，与4型大便之间存在关联。
other words we found associations
换句话说，我们发现膳食
between fiber intake and basically
纤维摄入量，尤其是
plant-based food intake and having a
植物性食物摄入量，与4型大便之间存在关联。这
number four so basically what that means
意味着，那些排出4型大便的
is the people that were having a number
人，往往更健康。
four bom movement were consuming more uh
四型便秘患者摄入更多
legumes whole grains fruits and
豆类、全谷物、水果和
vegetables the people who were having
蔬菜。
whether it be a type 1 or a type 7even
无论是1型便秘还是7型便秘，
they actually were quite similar in
他们的饮食其实非常相似，那就是
amount of fiber now the other thing to
纤维摄入量较低。另外需要
look at too is um actually some Studies
注意的是，一些研究
have found that people who have more on
发现，
the spectrum of constipation tend to
便秘程度较高的人往往
have a higher fat diet tend to typically
饮食中脂肪含量较高，通常
consume more animal products which of
摄入更多动物性食品，而动物性食品的脂肪含量自然也较高。
are more on the uh loose or diarrhea
腹泻患者则往往
side of things tend to be consuming more
摄入更多
plant-based Foods so now you could have
植物性食物。所以，即使
a very healthy diet and be having a
饮食非常健康，你的
Bristol f
布里斯托尔便秘分类也可能是F型，
and that actually is not problematic and
这其实并没有什么问题。
the reason that you're having the
出现
Bristol 5 is because you're consuming so
布里斯托尔5型便秘的原因是你摄入了
much fiber that actually you're
大量的纤维，导致体内
producing a lot of short chain fatty
产生大量短链
acids and those short chain fatty acids
脂肪酸。这些短链脂肪酸就像
they're like lubricants for your
润滑剂一样，可以促进
poop and the gut transition time how
粪便排出，缩短肠道蠕动时间。那么，这与
does that relate to these different
不同
types of poop as you were saying that I
类型的便秘有什么关系呢？正如你所说，我
was thinking the one and seven the type
想到的是1型和7型便秘。
one and the type seven the type one
1 型和 7 型，1 型指的
being those sort of hard nuts and the
是那种硬结，
type 7even being basically diarrhea I
7 型基本上就是腹泻。我
was assuming that those are the poop
假设这两种类型就是肠道蠕动时间
happen so with a lower and a super high
过长或过短时会出现的便便类型。
gut transition time that's right so a
没错，
slow gut Transit time which is a gut
肠道蠕动时间过长（
Transit time more than 58 hours so again
超过 58 小时）就属于这种情况。再说一遍，以上都是
and this is all with the blue muffins
关于蓝松饼的。
you eat the Blue Muffin it comes out 58
你吃了蓝松饼，58
hours later you are more likely to be
小时后才排出，你更有可能排出
having a Bristol one or Bristol 2 which
布里斯托尔 1 型或 2 型便便，这
is the classic constipation form there's
是典型的便秘类型。
gut Transit time and have a Bristol 7
肠道蠕动时间过长不可能出现布里斯托尔 7 型便便，这
that's not possible a diarrhea yeah yeah
是不可能的。腹泻，没错，
the diarrhea so diarrhea comes out fast
腹泻，腹泻排出很快，
and these sort of hard nuts they take
而那种硬结
typically a long time that's right and
通常需要很长时间才能排出。
the reason why this is happening you
这是因为，你
know um so when water moves through the
知道，当水流经肠道时，
intestines because a ton of water moves
因为大量的水会
through the intestines and one of the
流经肠道，而
jobs that our colon has the varge
我们结肠（
intestine is to pull the water out so
大肠）的功能之一就是…… 为了吸收水分，
the more time that something spends
食物
inside the colon the more it's actually
在结肠内停留的时间越长，吸收的水分就越多。
going to do that pull the water out this
这
is the reason why when we have fast
就是为什么肠道蠕动快时粪便含水量
Transit it's high in water and this is
高，而肠道
Transit it's extremely dry okay so
蠕动慢时粪便非常干燥的原因。好的，以上
that's the shape and size of the poop
是粪便的形状和大小，那么粪便的
but what about colors of poop I've got
颜色呢？我
some different colors of poop here I've
这里有一些不同颜色的粪便，有
got some red some blue some black some
红色、蓝色、黑色、
greens some whites and some yellows yes
绿色、白色和黄色。是的，
how is color pertinent to health and
颜色与健康和
everything we've been discussing all
我们一直在讨论的内容有什么关系呢？好的，
right let's break this down so first of
让我们来分析一下。
all why is our poop brown the answer to
首先，为什么我们的粪便是棕色的？
that question has to do with
这个问题的答案与
bile bile is produced by our liver it's
胆汁有关。胆汁由肝脏产生，它
actually involved heavily in digestion
实际上在脂肪消化中起着重要作用。
of fat so um when we for example eat a
例如，当我们吃一顿
fatty meal our gallbladder will squeeze
油腻的食物时，我们的胆囊会收缩。
people that have gallbladder issues know
有胆囊问题的人知道
what I'm talking about you eat a fatty
我在说什么，当你吃一顿油腻的
meal your gallbladder squeezes bile then
食物时，你的胆囊会挤出胆汁，然后胆汁
mixes in your intestines with the food
在肠道中与食物混合。
and the bile helps to absorb the fat um
胆汁有助于吸收脂肪，嗯，
that bile is what makes our poop brown
胆汁就是让我们的粪便变成棕色的原因。
if we're talking about a white poop
如果我们讨论的是白色粪便，这一点就显得尤为重要了。
people poop white some people poop white
有些人拉的是白色粪便，真的吗？是的。
no way yes and the reason why uh a
一个
person would have a white poop is if
人拉白色粪便的原因是肠道
there's a blockage that stops the bile
阻塞，阻止了胆汁
from mixing with their
与
intestines um on the flip side uh if you
肠道混合。另一方面，如果你
are struggling to process your fat you
难以消化脂肪，你的
could have a yellow poop so and this
粪便可能会是黄色的。
pancreas issue for example chronic
例如，患有胰腺疾病的人，比如慢性
pancreatitis and so if they're not able
胰腺炎，如果无法
to digest their fat they have a fatty
消化脂肪，就会拉出脂肪便，粪便
poop it may come out yellow
可能呈黄色。
and one of the things that they'll
他们会
notice is that there may be an oil slick
注意到的一点是，马桶顶部可能有一层油膜，对吧？那是
that's fat oil is fat so all right
脂肪，油就是脂肪。好的，
you've never had a have you ever had a
你从来没有拉过
green bow movement not old
绿色粪便吗？不是
business answer the da question I
老生常谈，回答这个问题。我
haven't okay um I have oh really yeah
没有。好的，嗯，我拉过。哦，真的吗？是的，
there's a couple reasons some are
原因有很多，有些是
healthy some are not so you could have a
健康的，有些是不健康的。所以
um you could have diarrhea like from an
你可能会…… 腹泻
infectious cause um an example could be
可能是由感染引起的，比如，
something called G yardia which is a
一种叫做G. yardia的
parasite mhm and that'll give you green
寄生虫，它会导致绿色
poop but you could also go too hard on
大便。但你也可能因为喝太多果昔而拉出绿色大便。
the smoothies I was drinking like 40
我以前每天喝40
ounces of green smoothies a day and my
盎司的绿色果昔，结果
poop would come out green was
大便就变成绿色的了，挺
interesting we're going to we're about
有意思的。接下来我们要讲
to get into some that are really
一些非常
important um before I do that let me
重要的，在此之前，我想先
just mention real quick the blue so the
快速提一下蓝色大便。
blue poo um you could get a blue poo
蓝色大便，吃蓝莓可能会导致蓝色大便，
blueberries um particularly if you eat a
尤其是吃
lot of them uh or alternatively of
很多蓝莓的时候。或者，当然，
course this is the Blue Muffin the blue
这就是所谓的“蓝色松饼
poo challenge so and perhaps what we
挑战”，也就是蓝色大便挑战。也许我们
could do in the show notes is give
可以在节目笔记里提供一下这个挑战的
people the recipe for how they can go
食谱，
about doing that if they if they're
如果有人
interested all right um red and
感兴趣的话。好的，接下来是红色和
black so we have to talk about let's
黑色大便。我们得谈谈这两种大便，先从
let's start with red because of course
红色开始，因为
red we think about
红色我们当然会想到
blood and um and I have a rule which is
血。我有一个原则，那就是
that if you see blood in your stool
如果大便里有血，
that's not
那就不
normal and to me that's grounds to talk
正常，对我来说，这是……
to a doctor and you know then there's
去看医生，你知道，医生会根据病情
seriously we check it out but Stephen
轻重缓急进行不同程度的检查。斯蒂芬，
colon cancer which can present with red
结肠癌的症状之一是
stool um colon cancer is the number two
大便带血。结肠癌是美国第二大
cause of cancer death in our
癌症死因，
people are diagnosed per
每年有15万人被诊断出患有此病。结肠癌
year it's highly
是高度
preventable and it's shifting towards
可预防的，而且发病人群正在向
people there has been a change in the
年轻人转移。近年来，结肠癌的发病率发生了变化。举个
where you know as an example a person of
例子，
uh your generation you and I are pretty
你我这一代人（我
close I think but I'm a little bit older
觉得我们年龄相仿，但我比你年长一些）
rectal cancer during their lifetime than
一生中患直肠癌的概率是
my parents were and twice twice times
我父母那一代人的四倍，患
more likely to be diagnosed with colon
结肠癌的概率是
cancer compared to my parents
我父母那
generation so there's been this shift
一代人的两倍。所以，这种变化已经发生，
and it's also affecting younger people
而且也影响到了年轻人。
so my point is this um I've had patients
我的意思是，我有很多这样的病人。
who come to me they go I saw a little
来找我的人会说：“我发现
bit of blood in my stool
大便里有一点血。”然后
do a colonoscopy and discover that they
去做结肠镜检查，结果发现他们肛门里
have a massive pop which is a precursor
有个很大的肿块，这是
cancer and by removing the pop we just
癌症的前兆。通过切除肿块，我们
basically stopped them from developing
基本上阻止了
cancer so I take it seriously when you
癌症的发生。所以，如果你
see a poop that is coated in red all
看到大便呈红色，我会非常重视。当然，
right now that red may be just on parts
红色可能只出现在部分大便上，
of it like it is here where uh that's
就像这里一样，
typically bright red coming from the
通常是鲜红色从肛门
bottom so that would be either something
底部流出。这可能意味着直肠里有东西，比如
hemorrhoids could be an anal fissure
痔疮、肛裂，
could also be a pup in the rectum okay
也可能是直肠里的脓肿。
but I think what I come back to is I
但我还是要强调，我
would encourage people to get checked
鼓励大家去做
out because just seeing the bright red
检查，因为仅仅看到鲜红色的
blood doesn't mean it's hemorrhoids
血并不一定就是痔疮，
don't assume that right particularly
不要想当然。尤其现在
with cancer shifting towards younger
癌症的发病率越来越年轻化，
people I think it's important to like
我认为这一点很重要。
get checked out on that point about
至于
cancer shifting towards younger people
癌症发病率越来越年轻化，
changing I think so I think it's I think
我认为这是因为我们的饮食习惯发生了改变。
it's I think it's um the shift
我认为这是
generationally that's taken place in
代际
terms of our diets um I also think that
饮食习惯转变的结果。 嗯，我也认为
there's a microbiome element the the
肠道菌群因素很重要。
connections between the gut microbiome
肠道菌群与结肠癌之间的联系与
powerful as any type of
其他类型的
cancer and at the same time what
癌症一样密切。同时，
protects us and I think you know where
保护我们的
I'm what I'm going to say it's the fiber
是膳食纤维
and the short chain fatty acids and in
和短链脂肪酸。
that study that I was mentioning earlier
我之前提到的
New Zealand um actually there there was
新西兰安德鲁·雷诺兹教授的研究表明，
a powerful association between fi
膳食纤维的
consumption and protecting ourselves
摄入量与预防
from colal cancer so powerful that for
结肠癌之间存在很强的关联。这种关联非常显著，
every gram five grams of fiber that we
我们每增加5克膳食纤维的摄入量，患结肠癌的
significant reduction in our risk so
风险就会显著降低。所以，关键
it's not just do you eat fiber or not
不在于你是否摄入膳食纤维，而在于你摄入
it's actually how much fiber do you eat
多少膳食纤维，摄入
and the more the better you know what I
越多越好。对了，我
should mention real quick red stool can
应该快速提一下，食用甜菜根
also come from eating beets uh it will
也可能导致大便呈红色。这种情况
almost always happen like literally you
几乎总是发生在
know 24 to 48 hours after you eat the
食用甜菜根后的24到48小时内。
beets so don't be surprised when that's
所以，如果出现这种情况，不要感到惊讶，
the case you may see a little bit of red
你可能会看到少量红色
stool um black stool can come from
大便。黑便也可能来自
benign places so an example is bismuth
良性因素，例如铋。
so like Pepto-Bismol so you have a you
就像服用必妥-比斯莫尔（Pepto-Bismol）一样，如果你
have a stomach ache and then you take
胃痛，就吃点必妥
some Pepto-Bismol
-比斯莫尔
and um so but the issue with this is
，嗯……但问题是，
it'll actually give you black stool so
它会导致黑便。所以，
if you're having a bad stomach for a
如果你
couple days in a row it could turn black
连续几天胃痛，大便就会变黑。
but the other thing that turns your
但还有一种也会导致
stool black that people need to know
大便变黑的情况，人们需要了解，那
about is a slow GI bleed bleeding into
就是缓慢的消化道出血，
specifically um because that bleeding is
特别是胃出血。因为出血
happening higher up in your intestines
发生在肠道上部，血液必须经过漫长的
through like intestinal Transit time
肠道传输时间才能到达直肠，所以当血液
the time it gets down to your rectum
到达直肠时，它就
it's now black it's not red anymore so
变黑了，不再是红色了。因此，黑
black stool can be indicative of of
便可能是
bleeding the way that we can
出血的征兆。我们可以
differentiate this is when it's blood it
区分黑便和血便的方法是，血便
smells terrible ah now we got to start
气味难闻。现在我们来闻闻大便。
smelling our inape yeah well you don't
嗯，你
have to stick your nose into it it's so
不用把鼻子凑过去闻，它很
clear like it would be so clear okay
清澈，就像……
okay when I'm in the hospital like I
我在医院里走来走去，
will be walking through and I can
我都能
literally tell when a consult is coming
闻出来…… 咨询马上就要开始了，
because I can smell this diagnosis
因为我感觉这诊断结果很准。
really yeah um so anyway the the stool
嗯，总之，大
will turn black it will smell terrible
便会变黑，气味难闻，像
and it will be like tar that's what
焦油一样。这和服用
for example take pept Bismol we released
例如Pept Bismol的情况不同。我们
it the first time and it sold out
第一次推出对话卡时，它
instantly we released conversation cards
瞬间售罄。我们再次推出对话卡，
again and they sold out instantly for a
也瞬间售罄。
second time we've updated the cards put
第二次，我们更新了卡片，加入了
all the new questions in and we've
所有新问题，并在
conversation cards now we've got
对话卡背面增加了一些新内容。现在，我们设置了
different levels of vulnerability so
不同程度的脆弱性。一级问题
level one these are more sort of surface
比较浅显，而到了
down to level three the questions become
三级，问题会变得更
a little bit more challenging a little
有挑战性，更需要你袒露
bit more vulnerable and that's really
心扉。这才是真正建立
where connection happens the brand new
联系的地方。全新的
version 2 updated conversation cards are
第二版更新对话卡现已
out right now at Theon conversation
在Theon conversationcards.com上线。
cards.com quick one as you might know a
顺便提一下，你可能知道，
company that I've invested in is now
我投资的一家公司现在
also a sponsor of this podcast and
也是这个播客的赞助商，
they're called Zoe and I'm coming to you
他们叫Zoe。
today with a warning it is January and
今天我要提醒大家，现在是1月，
it's all of those diet company's
这是所有减肥公司
favorite month of the year and that
一年中最喜欢的月份，这
means that you're about to hear a lot of
意味着你即将听到…… 在
jargon and words across all types of
各种媒体上，关于饮食文化充斥着大量的术语和词汇。
please don't get caught up in the fads
请不要盲目跟风，在
when it comes to your own health you
健康方面，你
must listen to experts and that's
必须听取专家的意见。而这正是
exactly what Zoe has Zoe isn't about
Zoe的理念。Zoe并非提倡
restriction or removing foods from your
限制或从饮食中剔除某些食物，
diet it's about building sustainable
而是帮助你建立可持续的
daily habits that will make your life
日常习惯，从而让你的生活更加
better forever they'll help you to
美好。他们会帮助你
discover how eating in the right way for
发现如何根据自身情况选择合适的饮食方式，也就是所谓的
personalized nutrition will have you
个性化营养，让你
feeling the benefits almost instantly
几乎立即感受到益处，
and far into the future if you're
并且这种益处会持续很久。如果你
looking to pick up new habits this year
想在今年养成一些
that will actually stick then use my
真正能够坚持下去的新习惯，那么请使用我的
code which is
优惠码
ce50 to
ce50，即可在
get50 off your Zoe kit for a limited
限时优惠中享受Zoe套装5折优惠，立即
time only use it right now I'm really
使用！我对“
we can give our gut microbiome to our
我们可以将肠道微生物群遗传给
kids but also in the twin studies they
孩子”这个想法非常感兴趣。双胞胎研究表明，他们的
have such a diverse gut microbiome so
肠道微生物群非常多样化，那么
how much of our gut microbiome are we
我们究竟
inheriting from our our parents our
从父母、祖父母等那里继承了多少肠道微生物群呢？
grandparents Etc if any at all well
如果有的话。
we're certainly inheriting some um and
我们当然会继承一些，
particularly when we're kids as a
尤其是在
newborn you're going to most closely
新生儿时期…… 婴儿的
resemble the gut microbiome of your
肠道菌群与母亲的肠道菌群最为接近，
mother and that that Association and
而且这种关联和
sharing is much more profound if you
共享在顺产和母乳喂养的情况下更为显著。
connection between Mom and baby actually
母婴之间的这种联系
helps to facilitate the transfer of
有助于
microbes to the baby that leads to
微生物向婴儿的转移，从而促进
health and this is part of the reason
健康。这也是
why when you disrupt these things which
为什么当我们破坏这些过程时（顺便
by the way I should mention sometimes
说一句，有时
these things are inevitable so I have
这些过程是不可避免的，比如我有
three kids they were all born by
三个孩子，都是
cesarean it's not the way that we wanted
剖腹产，这不是我们想要的，
it to be but it's what happened you can
但事实就是如此）。剖腹产也能
have healthy kids who are born by
生出健康的孩子。但是，
cesarean um so but uh when we disrupt
当我们破坏
these things whether it be cesarian
这些过程时，无论是剖腹产、
section or uh or bottle feeding instead
奶瓶喂养而不是
of breastfeeding or
母乳喂养，还是使用
antibiotics we see Downstream the same
抗生素，我们都会看到下游
effects increased likelihood of
效应：
obesity increased likelihood of allergic
肥胖的可能性增加、过敏性
conditions including food allergies and
疾病（包括食物过敏和
um
哮喘）的可能性增加、
autoimmune conditions including celiac
自身免疫性疾病（包括乳糜泻
disease and type 1
和1型
diabetes so when you disrupt the the dev
糖尿病）的可能性增加。所以，当我们破坏
veloping gut microbiome in that child um
儿童正在发育的肠道菌群时，
you increase the risk of these things
就会增加这些疾病发生的风险。目前已经有
some interesting studies where they will
一些有趣的研究结果。 一些研究
look at the microbiome they'll look in
会观察
the diaper of a child who's six months
六个月
or a year old and they can based upon
或一岁婴儿尿布里的微生物群，并以此
that they can predict who within the
预测
next four to five years is going to
未来四到五年内哪些人会
develop an allergic or autoimmune
患上过敏或自身免疫性
condition so so getting back to uh the
疾病。所以，回到
sharing of microbes like yes there is
微生物共享的话题，没错，
this connection between mom and child
母子之间确实存在这种联系，
but actually um this is an evolving
但实际上，这是一种贯穿
thing throughout our life and there's
我们一生的不断发展的过程。一项
important about human connection and in
关于人际关系的新研究我认为非常重要。
this study what they found is that
这项研究发现，
through connection uh they number one
通过人际关系共享空间的人，首先
had a healthier gut microbiome than
比独居的人拥有更健康的肠道微生物群；
themselves number two they share more
其次，他们之间共享的
microbes together so like for example me
微生物更多。例如，我
with my wife um we share more microbes
和我的妻子共享的微生物
together than I do with my siblings wow
比我和我的兄弟姐妹共享的还要多。哇！
of fascinating from this study is the um
这项研究另一个令人着迷的发现是，
the strength of the relationship
人际关系的牢固程度
matters so uh I think we can all agree
至关重要。我想我们都同意，
sometimes relationships are in a good
人际关系有时
place and sometimes they're in a bad
很好，有时很糟糕，
place right and that's like a whole
这就像一个
spectrum and different conversation but
光谱，需要另行讨论。但
actually where it is on that Spectrum
实际上，…… 研究表明，
impacts your gut microbiome they found
肠道菌群会影响你的肠道微生物群。研究发现，
that the couples that were sharing uh
共享
the most microbes were the ones that
微生物最多的伴侣，
actually had the most um Connection in
在关系上也拥有最紧密的联系；
terms of their relationship whereas the
而那些
people who were disconnected from one
彼此疏远的人，
another they weren't sharing so many
共享的
microbes now you could say like is that
微生物就很少。你可能会问，这是
because they're having less sex could it
因为他们性生活较少吗？还是因为他们在
be that they just like physically aren't
身体上
even close to one another I suppose
彼此疏远？我想这些都有
that's all possible but these are also
可能。但这些研究
people where they like they controlled
对象都控制了
for their diet so it's not a dietary
饮食，所以这并非饮食
thing so like I think that the you know
问题。因此，我认为，
the takeaway from my
从我的
perspective is the power of human
角度来看，关键在于人际
connection is more important in 202 3
联结的力量在2023年和2024年比以往任何时候都更加重要。我们
aspects of our life are pulling us away
生活的许多方面都在将我们与
from this our devices social media I
这种联结拉开距离——我们的电子设备和社交媒体。我的
mean I'm very active on social media but
意思是，我本人也经常使用社交媒体，但
let's be transparent about this this is
坦白地说，这正在
pulling us away from the ability to sit
剥夺我们
down with another person look them in
与另一个人坐下来，看着
the eye talk to them have a meaningful
对方的眼睛交谈，进行有意义的
conversation and feel connected to that
对话，并感受到彼此联结的能力。
person and because you feel connected
因为你感觉 与人建立联系，
you reap the rewards which do include
你就能收获回报，其中包括
better got Health but but that's super
更好的健康。这非常
interesting because it yeah it does make
有趣，因为它确实表明，我们
a case that the people we surround
身边的人会影响我们的心理健康。
psychology right we tend to think that
我们往往会从心理学的角度来思考这个问题，认为与
you surround yourself with a certain
某种
type of person it's good for your
类型的人相处对你的
psychology if they're positive or
心理健康有益，无论他们是积极的还是
they're negative Etc but there's
消极的等等。但
actually a case that people the people
实际上，
we surround ourselves with have an
我们身边的人也会
impact on our physiology our bodies Our
影响我们的生理机能、身体、
biology our gut microbiome and that has
生物学、肠道菌群，这种影响会从源头上渗透到
an upstream effect on everything that's
方方面面。这是
true but you also can't disentangle or
事实，但你也不能忽视
positive influence of a person also
一个人的积极影响同样
really matters yeah because where you're
重要。因为你的
at from an emotional perspective and I
情绪状态——我
think this is an important thing for
认为这一点很重要——
does manifest in your gut health and
会影响你的肠道健康。
this is the reason why for example if a
这就是为什么，例如，如果一个
person is going to go and do public
人要进行公开
speaking and they're not comfortable
演讲，而他并不擅长
with public speaking they may just have
公开演讲，他可能只会感到
a little bit of jitters a little bit of
轻微的紧张、
nausea or queasiness but it can also uh
恶心或不适，但这种不适感可能会像
snowball into something bigger and worse
滚雪球一样越滚越大。 压力可能会演变成更严重、更剧烈的症状，
such as fold fold you over type cramps
比如剧烈的痉挛。
right so and that's many people will
很多人会把
manifest their stress in their gut
压力表现在肠胃上，这
that's an acute example by acute I mean
是一个急性例子。我说的急性是指你目前
that you're uh involved with but what
所处的特定情境。但
happens if your life is
如果你的生活充满
stress and the answer to that question
压力呢？答案
is actually very clear because people
其实很明确，因为
who for example have childhood trauma
例如有童年创伤的人，
more likely to develop digestive issues
更容易出现消化问题和
but other gut related issues and there
其他肠道相关问题。
was an interesting study Stephen that
斯蒂芬做过一项有趣的研究，研究对象是
two-year-olds um who were
两岁的被
adopted and uh and they studied the gut
收养儿童。研究人员研究了
microbiome of these kids and downstream
这些孩子的肠道微生物群，并发现，
adopted home even though it was before
即使他们两岁之前就被收养，甚至
Age 2 like they can't remember this even
不记得这件事，但被收养的经历仍然会
affected their gut microbiome it
影响他们的肠道微生物群，
affected their response to stress and it
影响他们对压力的反应，也会
also affected the way that their brain
影响他们的大脑运作方式。研究人员
show this through functional M
通过功能性M
technology where they looked at the
技术证实了这一点，他们观察了
brain and how was how it was activating
大脑的激活情况。
just because of that sort of early
因为那种早期
trauma early trauma so and not not you
创伤，所以……当然，
know not everyone who has got issues has
并不是说所有有问题的人都
been exposed to trauma but um I think
经历过创伤，但我认为
it's important for people to understand
重要的是让人们明白，
that if you have been exposed to trauma
如果你经历过创伤，
this can be a very important part of
这可能是你康复过程中非常重要的一部分。
your healing process that's the message
这就是我想传达的信息。我之所以要传达
and the reason why I bring that message
这个信息，
is because I've had people who are in my
是因为我
clinic and they're like Dr B I do
诊所里有些人会说：“B医生，我完全按照
everything that you tell me to do and I
您说的去做，我按部就班地吃饭、
do it by the book I eat I sleep I
睡觉、
exercise I do yoga I do medit and I
锻炼、做瑜伽、
meditate and despite that they're not
冥想，尽管如此，他们的病情并没有
getting better and in in those
好转。” 在这些治疗
relationships what ends up happening is
关系中，
typically after a couple of visits we
通常几次就诊后，我们会
start to get comfortable with one
彼此熟悉、互相信任。
another we trust one another and when
当
you get to that place they will share
达到这种程度时，他们会向我倾诉他们的经历。
and then I make it clear this is the
然后我会清楚地告诉他们，这就是
reason why when you heal the wound of
为什么当你治愈
the trauma you actually heal the gut and
创伤的伤口时，你的肠道也会得到修复。
it's amazing because they're like a
这很神奇，因为他们就像
rocket ship because they're doing all
火箭一样，因为他们做的一切都是
the right stuff right they're they're
正确的——他们
eating right sleeping right exercising
吃得好、睡得好。 正确的锻炼方式，一旦
and the minute you take away this thing
你解除
that is chaining them down and holding
束缚他们的枷锁，一旦
them back the minute you release those
你松开这些
chains They Shoot To the Moon and it's
枷锁，他们就会如离弦之箭般冲向月球，那感觉真是太棒了。
I would say that like in my clinical
在我的临床
career that has been the most rewarding
生涯中，这绝对是最有意义的
thing above anything else far more than
事情，远胜于
like getting a person to eat more fiber
让病人多吃纤维。那么酒精呢？
what about alcohol I've recently quit
我最近戒酒了。很
drinking alcohol I'm glad you did why
高兴你这么做了。
are you glad I did well let me be the
你为什么高兴我戒酒？
first to say that um I have not
嗯，首先我要说，我还没有
completely quit consuming alcohol but if
完全戒酒。但如果
we remove my imperfect self from this
我们抛开我个人的不完美，只看
picture and just look at the science the
科学，
science is actually quite clear our gut
科学已经很清楚地表明，
is damaged by alcohol so let's take a
酒精会损害我们的肠道。所以，让我们先
step back for a moment
退一步想想，
if I want to clean this table right
如果我想清洁这张桌子，好了，
we're all done we want to clean it up
我们都完成了，我们要把它清理干净，
what are we going to do we pull out
我们会怎么做？我们会拿出
rubbing alcohol it destroys
酒精，它可以杀死
microbes alcohol destroys
微生物。酒精可以杀死
microbes and when we drink to the point
微生物。当我们喝酒到
of having a hangover is that
宿醉的程度时，那是
dehydration absolutely not and I'm of
脱水吗？绝对不是。
the belief based upon the research that
根据
I've seen that what's happening when
我看到的研究，我相信当
you're uh having a hangover is that you
你…… 宿醉意味着
have caused significant damage to your
你的
microbiome and this is the reason why it
肠道菌群受到了严重破坏，这就是为什么
takes 24 hours or more for you actually
你需要24小时甚至更长时间才能恢复正常的原因。
again what you see with alcohol is
酒精的危害令人担忧，它
disturbing it's more than just liver
不仅仅会导致
disease there are many different Health
肝病，还有许多其他健康
rated conditions that are tied back to
问题都与饮酒有关。
we've set where we say people it's okay
我们设定的饮酒阈值，比如
have up to three drinks a day as a guy
男性每天最多三杯，
or up to two drinks a day as a woman
女性每天最多两杯，都算是适量饮酒，这在
like that to me is ridiculous that's a
我看来简直荒谬，这
lot but the study that changed
太多了。但真正改变
everything for me was where they
我看法的，是一项
actually monitored um levels of
监测
something called bacterial endotoxin or
细菌内毒素或
lipopolysaccharide this is something
脂多糖水平的研究。这种物质
that is not supposed to be in our
不应该存在于我们的
bloodstream when it is in our
血液中，而当它出现在
bloodstream it's because there's been
血液中时，是因为
damage to the gut
肠道
barrier and it causes inflammation this
屏障受到了破坏，并引发了炎症。这正是
is the exact same thing that can cause
导致
us to get extremely sick but at a
我们生病的原因，
minimum it is causing inflammation in
至少它会引起体内炎症。这项
and um they did a study where they were
研究
basically
主要
monitoring levels of this
监测了这种
lipopolysaccharide after alcohol
脂多糖的水平。 研究表明，饮酒后，
blood alcohol levels and what they
血液酒精浓度升高，脂多糖水平也升高，两者呈
parallel
平行关系：
lines blood alcohol level goes up
血液酒精浓度升高，
lipopolysaccharide level goes up blood
脂多糖水平也降低；血液酒精浓度升高，
lipopolysaccharide level turns down they
脂多糖水平也降低，两者
were the exact same thing
完全一致。
so when I saw that to me even when we're
因此，即使我们只
consuming minimal amounts of alcohol we
摄入少量酒精，也
are potentially causing problems for our
可能对
gut microbes what is the brain gut
肠道微生物造成损害。什么是脑-肠
connection so the brain gut connection
连接？脑-肠连接
is referring to the fact that um your
指的是，
gut's best friend is the brain they're
肠道最好的朋友就是大脑。它们正在
talking to each other right now and they
相互交流，密不可分，这是
are inseparable you can't get away from
无法回避的。
your gut will talk to the brain so part
肠道与大脑交流的方式有很多种，其中一种
of it is the release of
是释放神经
neurotransmitters
递质。
95% of the serotonin in your body is
人体内95%的血清素是
produced by the gut serotonin is the
由肠道产生的。血清素是
happy hormone it's what makes us feel
快乐激素，它让我们感到
energized um it's what gives us great
精力充沛，
mood and in some ways also also gives us
心情愉悦，并在某种程度上帮助我们集中
Focus you would think that it comes from
注意力。你可能会认为它来自
your brain you know when we treat a
大脑，但当我们治疗
person with major depression we treat
重度抑郁症患者时，我们会……
them to increase serotonin levels yet
为了提高血清素水平，我们采取了一些措施，但
actually is produced inside your brain
实际上，人体内只有5%的血清素是在大脑中产生的，
95% of it is produced within your gut
95%是在肠道中产生的。
serotonin can signal the brain through a
血清素可以通过一条
nerve called the Vegas nerve the Vegas
叫做迷走神经的神经向大脑发出信号。迷走
nerve is like a super phone between the
神经就像
brain and the gut it would be like uh if
大脑和肠道之间的一条超级电话线。这就好比，如果
you were in London and I were in the
你在伦敦，我在
United States and I had a direct line to
美国，我有一条直通你的线路，我拿起电话说：“
yo Stephen I need to talk to you right
嘿，斯蒂芬，我需要和你谈谈。” 这就是
that's the way that this works your gut
它的运作方式：你的肠道通过
that phone line so serotonin
这条“电话线”直接与大脑对话。所以，血清素、
dopamine 50% of dopamine which is the
多巴胺——其中50%的多巴胺（一种
reward hormone produced in the gut there
奖赏激素）是在肠道中产生的——
in the gut there's also the Vagas nerve
肠道会产生超过30种神经递质。此外，还有我们刚才提到的迷走神经。
finally your gut is producing
最后，肠道还会产生一些
metabolites
代谢产物，例如后生元，它们
postbiotics that can cross into the
可以进入
brain and have an effect we mentioned
大脑并产生影响。我们之前提到过，
from fiber have the ability to cross the
来自膳食纤维的短链脂肪酸能够穿过
blood brain barrier and actually
血脑屏障，
influence things like our mood our Focus
影响我们的情绪和注意力。
there was one study with kids where by
有一项针对儿童的研究表明， 通过
increasing short chain fatty acids for
增加这些孩子体内的短链脂肪酸，
those kids they actually were able to
他们确实能够
increase their focus because they were
提高注意力，因为他们之前存在
having trouble with Focus you've
注意力不集中的问题。您
in your book you said I you believe that
在书中反复提到纤维和您所说的短链脂肪酸，您认为
they're the most healing nutrient in all
它们是自然界中最具疗愈作用的营养物质。
nature I think that's actually true and
我认为这确实如此，而且
I also would um characterize them as the
我还会将它们描述为
I've ever come across and am I right in
我所见过的最强的抗炎分子。我的理解是，
thinking we eat fiber the bacteria in
我们摄入纤维后，
our microbiome break breaks down that
我们肠道菌群中的细菌会分解
fiber and it produces this thing these
纤维，产生
short chain fatty acids right is that it
短链脂肪酸，对吗？就是这样。
that's that's I hav the story is just
故事才刚刚
getting started though okay yeah the
开始。是的，
story is just getting started because
故事才刚刚开始，因为
the issue is that that's the simple part
问题在于，这只是简单的部分。
right these these magicians that live
这些生活
inside of US release these short chain
在
fatty acids for us by eating fiber by
我们体内的“魔法师”通过
eating fiber or or resistant starches
摄入纤维或抗性淀粉来释放短链脂肪酸。然后，
okay but then um then those short chain
这些短链
fatty acids go to work and our uh our
脂肪酸开始发挥作用，我们的
immune
免疫
cells our human cells have receptors to
细胞，也就是人体细胞，拥有
receive these short chain fatty acids
接收这些短链脂肪酸的受体，
and act upon the information that they
并根据接收到的信息采取行动。
receive so you could think of them as
您可以把它们想象成…… 从
like a signaling molecule in the sense
某种意义上说，
that your gut microbiome is not talking
肠道微生物群就像信号分子，它不会直接
to your body and telling your body what
与你的身体沟通，告诉身体
it wants your body to do so it's
它想要做什么，而是在训练身体。是的，它能够开启或关闭
ability to like flip genes off and on
基因，甚至能够
okay it has the ability to turn down
抑制
your immune system so as an example when
免疫系统。举个例子，
I think about autoimmune conditions if
如果我们深入研究自身免疫性疾病，就会
you would discover is that we need more
发现我们需要更多的
short chain fatty acids to empower these
短链脂肪酸来增强一种
specific cells called t- regulatory
叫做调节性T细胞的特定细胞的功能。
cells and those T regulatory cells would
这些调节性T细胞
actually turn down our immune system and
实际上会抑制我们的免疫系统，从而
protect us so and and it's not to say
保护我们。当然，这并不是说
that autoimmune diseases are exclusively
自身免疫性疾病完全是由
the result of a fiber
纤维
deficiency um there is certainly a
缺乏引起的，它们肯定有
genetic component but there was a
遗传因素。
genetic component 200 years ago 300
200年前、300年前就存在遗传因素，
years ago and yet those these conditions
但当时这些疾病并不是什么大
really weren't that much of a problem
问题。
back then so many of these conditions
很多这类疾病
didn't have a name until the last 100
直到近100年才被命名。
years and um and the emergence of them
而且，
many of them have increased 500% in the
很多疾病在
last 50 years why would that be it
过去50年里增加了500%，这是为什么呢？
clearly is not genetics so it has to be
显然…… 不是基因问题，所以肯定
related to our diet and lifestyle and
和我们的饮食和生活方式有关。
ultimately when we talk about our diet
归根结底，当我们谈论饮食
and lifestyle we're talking about our
和生活方式时，我们其实是在谈论我们的
microbiome and really the one of the
肠道菌群。
most important places to start as you
正如你所说，最重要的起点之一就是膳食
say is with the fiber I think so and you
纤维，我认为是这样。你
said earlier on we have to start slowing
之前也说过，我们必须从低纤维开始，慢慢增加纤维的摄入量。
and low with fiber yeah and that's
这是
because we've got to build up those
因为我们需要建立起那些能够
microbes that respond to the fiber and
对纤维做出反应并将
turn it into the short chain fatty acids
其转化为短链脂肪酸的微生物群。
right your gut is like a muscle right
你的肠道就像一块肌肉，对吧？
like this is this is the way that I want
我希望
people to understand this your gut is
大家能这样理解：你的肠道就像
like a muscle and a muscle is capable of
一块肌肉。 肌肉虽然能够
work but it has
工作，但也有其
limitations and the more that the muscle
局限性。肌肉训练得越多，
work it is so if you um lift weights you
工作能力就越强。举重的话，你
might start at 50
可能从50
kilos if we're doing a bench press you
公斤开始；做卧推的话，你
kilos and then you go to 55 kilos and
公斤开始，然后增加到55公斤，
then the 60 kilos and you work your way
再到60公斤，
up and that's the process of growing
循序渐进。这就是
strong and your gut works the exact same
肌肉增长的过程。肠道的运作方式也完全相同。
way so if you expose your gut to
如果你让肠道接触
food specifically a diverse mix of
食物，特别是各种
different foods you are training your
不同的食物，你就是在训练你的
gut and your gut will become more
肠道。随着时间的推移，你的肠道会越来越
capable of consuming those Foods over
能消化这些食物。
time and then you can eventually get to
最终，你就可以达到无需
restrict based upon your capabilities
限制饮食的程度，
because the capabilities are
因为你的消化能力是
Limitless now you can eat whatever you
无限的。现在你可以想吃什么就吃什么。
want and is all fiber the same no not
所有的纤维都一样吗？不，并非
all fiber is the same fiber is a very
所有纤维都一样。纤维是一个非常
generic word fiber is like the word
笼统的词，就像
protein no one would claim that the
蛋白质一样。没有人会说
protein in a fish is the same as a
鱼肉中的蛋白质和
protein in a bean yet both of them
豆类中的蛋白质一样，但它们都
contain
含有
protein fiber is unique to individual
蛋白质。纤维是每种
plants there are many many different
植物特有的，纤维有很多不同的
forms of fiber to the point that we
形式，多到我们
don't even know how many exist so what
无法一一列举。 我们甚至不知道究竟有多少种纤维存在，所以
we know is this it's rather simple
我们所知道的是，
though right given despite that
尽管纤维种类
complexity it's rather simple all plants
繁多，但其实很简单，对吧？所有植物都
contain
含有
fiber every single plant has unique
纤维，每种植物的
forms of fiber we do split it into two
纤维形式都各不相同。我们将其分为两大
major types these are again umbrella
类，这些只是
labels soluble and insoluble
统称，是可溶性纤维和不溶性
fiber the soluble fiber is the kind that
纤维。可溶性纤维可以
dissolves in a drink it disappears you
溶解在饮料中，几乎
don't even know that it's there yet
感觉不到它的存在。
typically the soluble fiber is feeding
通常情况下，可溶性纤维会为微生物提供营养，这就是所谓的“
fiber in it so insoluble fiber most of
营养纤维”。不溶性纤维就像颗粒一样，即使你把它添加到饮料中，它也不会溶解，它会一直存在。即使你把饮料煮沸，里面仍然会有纤维。所以，大多数情况下，不
the time is not the preotic fiber but it
溶性纤维并不是营养纤维，但它
does still serve a purpose it helps in
仍然有其作用。它有助于
bowel movements which affects your gut
肠道蠕动，从而影响肠道微生物；它有助于促进排便，从而影响肠道微生物；
microbes it helps in terms of other
它还有助​​于控制
things such as your cholesterol and your
胆固醇和血脂等其他方面。
control so both types of fiber both
因此，
soluble and insoluble have advantages
可溶性纤维和不溶性纤维各有益处。
you don't need to worry about those
不必单独担心这些，
individually you just need to know that
你只需要知道
plants have fiber every single plant has
植物含有纤维，每种植物都有其
a unique form of fiber and every single
独特的纤维形式，每种
plant will feed unique families of
植物都会为独特的
microbes as a result of this you have
微生物群落提供养分。因此，你
these F goals you talk about in the book
在书中
when you're recommending diets that you
推荐饮食方案时会提到“F目标”，
think people should consider and I think
我认为
it's important because this word diet is
这很重要，因为“节食”这个词本身就带有
quite stigmatized right and it can lead
污名，而且可能会
to like disordered eating and things
导致饮食失调
like that so I think it's important for
等等问题。所以我认为有必要
us to talk about that a little bit but I
稍微讨论一下这个问题。但我确实
do want to know what these F goals are
想知道这些“F目标”是什么。
and when you use the word diet you're
当你使用“节食”这个词时，你
not saying something that's
并不是在说某种
unsustainable and short in order to have
不可持续的、
a shortterm I'm saying actually the
短期的饮食方式。实际上，我的意思
opposite like I want people to have
恰恰相反，我希望人们拥有
abundance in fact I would if you were to
丰富的饮食。事实上，如果你
ask me what is the biggest misconception
问我肠道健康领域最大的误解是什么，
that exists in the gut health space my
我的
answer to that question would be that
答案是
people are very quick to
人们很容易
restrict and less quick to add back so
限制饮食，却很难恢复正常饮食。
with regard to F goals um this is my
关于“F目标”，嗯，这是我的
general framework it is not the like
总体框架，它并非
only thing but this is my general
唯一框架，但这是
framework for how I remember to organize
我记忆的总体框架。 为了安排
my day in terms of foods that I'm trying
我一天的饮食，我特意用
out each letter represents different
字母来代表不同的
categories of food so F fruit um I think
食物类别。比如，F代表水果，我觉得
fruit has been in appropriately uh
水果被
villainized I think fruit's amazingly
妖魔化了，其实水果
good for us in fact people that consume
对我们非常有益。事实上，多吃水果的人患
diabetes they also lose
糖尿病的风险更低，而且还能
weight fermented uh we've talked about
减肥。发酵食品，我们之前也讨论过，
your microbiome by adding fermented food
多吃发酵食品可以增加肠道菌群的多样性。
we need this g g stands for Greens
我们需要这些。G代表绿叶蔬菜，绿叶
Greens have almost no calories yet tons
蔬菜几乎不含卡路里，但
of nutrition that's good and Grains by
营养丰富，这很好。
grains I don't mean refined
谷物，我指的不是精制
grains I mean unrefined grains so like
谷物，而是未精制的谷物，比如
whole grains so good for us those are
全谷物。这些
gut microbiome foods high in fiber and
食物富含纤维和
um resistant starches o stands for
抗性淀粉，对肠道菌群有益。O代表
omega-3 superp seeds so that's Chia flax
omega-3超级种子，比如奇亚籽、亚麻籽、大麻籽
hemp and also walnuts um those contain
和核桃。这些都含有
omega-3 fats those are healthy fats that
omega-3脂肪酸，是
we need more of a stands for aromatics
我们需要的健康脂肪。A代表香料，
so that's onions garlic shallots they're
比如洋葱、大蒜和青葱。它们
delicious they're also great for your
美味可口，而且营养丰富。 为了你的
heart and protect you from
心脏健康，也为了预防
cancer L is legumes so uh legumes
癌症，L代表豆类，豆类
includes beans peas and lentils um I
包括豆子、豌豆和扁豆。我
would go back to saying like to me this
会再次强调，对我来说，豆类
is the number one the number one
是排名第一的
superfood um because they're gut health
超级食物，因为它们有益肠道健康，
foods and they're longevity foods and if
而且是延年益寿的食物。如果
we look at the evidence with heart
我们看看心脏病、
disease cancer stroke diabetes all all
癌症、中风、糖尿病等各种疾病的证据，
across the board you're going to see
你会发现
these reduce your likelihood of having
豆类可以降低患
those
这些
diseases um s i when I got to S I kind
疾病的风险。说到S的时候，我有点
of lost my mind because I felt like I
语无伦次了，因为我觉得还
have more that want to say so let me
有很多话想说，所以我就简单
just pack it all in so s stands for
总结一下。S代表
mushrooms um technically are not plants
蘑菇，蘑菇严格来说不是植物，而是
they're fungi but they contain fiber and
真菌，但它们含有纤维，
are incredibly good for us so they are
对我们非常有益，所以它们也算是“
honorary plants um s also stands for
荣誉植物”。S也代表
seaweed so most cultures don't consume
海藻，大多数文化都不食用
seaweed but like for example in Japan
海藻，但比如在日本，
they do and they're incredibly healthy
人们会食用海藻，而且海藻对健康非常有益。海藻
as a result of this it's another source
是另一种
of unique types of plants with unique
独特的植物，富含独特的
sources of fiber and the last is I'm
纤维。最后，我
going to in the book I said
在书中提到了
sulfurane which refers to a cancer
硫磺，它指的是…… 西兰花芽中含有一种抗癌
fighting chemical that you will find in
化学物质，
Sprouts but um I want to re rephrase
但我想重新表述一下，
this to say Sprouts so Sprouts to me are
说说芽苗菜。对我来说，芽苗菜是
superfoods there's something magical
超级食物，它蕴含着神奇的力量。
that happens what is a sprout by the way
顺便说一下，芽苗菜是什么？有些
for people who are wondering you could
人可能想知道，你可以
take any um any
拿任何
seed um and if you quite simply Add
种子，只要加
Water you will unlock nature because
水，就能唤醒它，因为
basically that seed is waiting to
种子本身就处于等待
germinate and grow so when you enter
发芽生长的状态。当你用水“
this code of B Bally like unlocking it
激活”它时，
with water it comes to life it opens up
它就活了过来，破土而出，
and outshoots this plant and that that
长出了幼苗。这种
plant is the Sprout and the Sprout is
幼苗富含
tremendously high in fiber protein but
纤维、蛋白质以及植物
also phytochemicals there's unique
化学物质。这些独特的
chemicals that you will find in these
化学物质含量远高于其他
plants in a in a disproportionate level
植物，比如
compared to for example you know uh I
我刚才
mentioned broccoli Sprouts broccoli
提到的西兰花芽。西兰花芽的
fighting chemical than adult broccoli
抗癌化学物质含量是成熟西兰花的50到100倍。
has so eating a pinch of broccoli
所以，吃一小撮西兰
Sprouts can have you can provide just as
花芽就能获得和成熟西兰花一样
much benefit as eating ahead of broccoli
多的益处。 吃西兰花之前先吃点东西，这很
so interesting so if you're a parent and
有意思。如果你是一位家长，并且
you follow the F goals diet that you lay
遵循你在书中提出的F目标饮食法，
out in your book The interesting thing I
我
found is if you're a mother and you're
发现有趣的是，如果你是一位母亲，并且正在孕育
having a child you're then going to pass
一个孩子，那么你会将
on some of your microbiome to that child
你的一些微生物群传递给孩子。
and and also I was reading about that
我还读到一项
mice study conducted um that shows how
小鼠研究，该研究表明
the Western diet induces a loss of
西方饮食如何导致
microbial diversity that can compound
微生物多样性的丧失，这种丧失会
over a series of generations yeah that
代代相传。是的，这
was a Justin sonenberg study so Justin
是贾斯汀·索嫩伯格（Justin Sonenberg）的研究。贾斯汀·索
sonenberg is a guy that I'm a big fan of
嫩伯格是我非常欣赏的一位学者，
he's out in Stanford and he actually um
他在斯坦福大学任教，他还为
wrote a blurb on my first book fiber
我的第一本书《纤维领域》（Fiber Field）写了推荐语。
field and so um the issue is that we
问题是，我们
want to understand microbial loss that
想要了解微生物群落的
can occur over Generations because
代际丧失，因为
clearly our generation is different than
很明显，我们这一代与
our grandparents mhm and it's hard to do
我们的祖父母辈不同。这对于人类来说很难做到，
with humans because it takes us like you
因为如今我们人类需要
know these days 30 or more years to
30年甚至更长时间才能
create a new generation so but with mice
繁衍出新一代。但是对于小鼠来说，
you can do this very quickly M so he
你可以很快地做到这一点。所以，他
basically started off with mice with a
首先研究了具有
certain level of microbial diversity um
一定微生物多样性水平的小鼠。
the diversity of the microbiome is a
微生物组是衡量
microbiome and then he saw what happened
微生物组健康状况的指标。他观察了
with a low fiber diet and so basically
低纤维饮食的影响。
what he saw is that if you put them on a
他发现，如果让小鼠食用
low fiber diet that Mouse will start to
低纤维食物，小鼠的微生物组多样性就会开始
lose diversity and then it will transfer
下降，并将这种下降遗传给后代。而这些后代如果
still on a low fiber diet continues to
继续食用低纤维食物，也会继续
lose diversity and transfer that onto
下降多样性，并将这种下降遗传给
their offspring and so on and what he
它们的后代，如此循环往复。他
found was that if during this process
发现，如果在这个过程中进行
you intervene and you add back the
干预，补充膳食
fiber you can actually restore on some
纤维，实际上可以在一定
level the diversity within the microb
程度上恢复微生物
bom you can wake them back up they can
组的多样性，唤醒它们，使它们恢复活力。
come back but the issue is you won't get
但问题是，你无法完全
all the way back to the starting point
恢复到初始状态。由于
Generations if your grandmother has
几代人不断做出选择，已经造成了一定程度的损失。假设你的祖母小时候
1,200 species of microbes in her gut as
肠道内有1200种微生物，
a child but by the time your mother was
但到你母亲出生时只剩下
900 that's what your mother got yep then
900种，那么
if your mother loses 300 species in her
你母亲的
microbiome now you start off with 600
微生物组就只剩下600种了。
half of what your grandmother originally
你祖母最初的想法是对的，
had right and at some point the loss of
但在某种程度上，
those species becomes problematic
这些物种的消失会成为问题，
because um each of those species is
因为每个物种的存在都有其
there with a purpose we evolved to have
目的，我们进化到拥有
them and when they're absent they're not
它们，当它们消失时，它们就
able to do their job and the other
无法履行职责，其他
microbes may not be able to step up to
微生物也可能无法填补空缺。
missing it's just such a great case that
这是一个很好的例子，说明
you know keeping ourselves healthy is
保持我们自身的健康
keeping our children healthy as well in
在很多方面也意味着保持我们孩子的健康，
many respects and we also live with our
而且我们和
children so we're creating an ecos
孩子一起生活，所以我们
system in our homes
在家里创造了一个由
of these microbes on everything I think
这些微生物构成的生态系统，我认为
that's completely true and um and and I
这一点完全正确。而且，我
also think that like when we think about
认为当我们考虑
um generational issues that exist so you
存在的代际问题时，
know you in many studies they'll say if
很多研究会说，如果
your parents had this then you're at
你的父母患有这种疾病，那么你也有患病的风险，
risk for this and we have assumed that
我们一直假设
these are genetic things yet much of the
这些是遗传因素造成的，但很多
genetic research much of which has been
遗传研究——其中很多是
done by Tim Spectre uh my partner at
由我的合作伙伴蒂姆·斯佩克特（Tim Spectre）在
Zoe much of that has not played out to
Zoe公司完成的——并没有
prove that it is in fact
证明这确实是
genetic I think what's happening is not
遗传因素。我认为，现在发生的事情不仅仅是
just the transfer of microbes I think
微生物的传播。
it's also the transfer of
这也是
lifestyle and the lifestyle that gets
生活方式的传承，而
transferred by generation is um if it's
代代相传的生活方式，如果是
unhealthy then unfortunately you're
不健康的，那么很不幸，你也会把随之而来的
transferring along the problems that
问题一起传递下去。这很
come with that MH interesting so you're
有意思，你不仅
transferring the lifestyle and the
传递了生活方式，还传递了那些
microbes which weren't able to deal with
无法适应这种
the lifestyle that caused a disease
生活方式并导致疾病的微生物。
right so
所以，很
interesting sexual attraction is the
有意思。
last thing I want to talk to you about
最后我想和你谈谈性
sexual attraction in the the gut microb
吸引力，以及你之前提到的肠道微生物群中的性吸引力，比如
you mentioned earlier sort of erectile
勃起功能障碍。还有
dysfunction there's pheromones there's
信息素，以及
all these sort of sexual components that
所有这些性相关的因素，它们
lead us to having a great sex life what
能让我们拥有美好的性生活。那么，
the gut microbiome and sex and ere good
肠道微生物群与性、良好的
erections and desire and libido if any
勃起、性欲和性冲动之间究竟存在怎样的联系或分离呢？
at all first of all I think it's quite
首先，我认为很
clear that when people are sick which of
明显，当人们生病时（
course they have a uh damaged gut
当然，他们的肠道微生物群会受损），
they're not the libido is gone right
性欲就会消失。
that's a part of that territory libido
这是其中的一部分。性欲
is also associated with
也与
hormones and there's a number of
激素有关，而
different hormones that our gut microbes
我们的肠道微生物群能够影响多种不同的激素，例如
have the ability to impact for women
女性的雌
estrogen there's a term that's called
激素。 有一个术语叫做雌激素
and estrobolome sounds a little bit like
代谢组（estrobolome），它听起来有点像
microbiome because basically what we're
微生物组（microbiome），因为我们基本上
referring to are the microbes that
指的是
control estrogen levels in women so the
控制女性体内雌激素水平的微生物。
gut microbiome creat estrogen it
肠道微生物组产生雌激素，并
controls the recirculation of estrogen
控制雌激素的循环。
okay so estrogen has this circular
雌激素的
circular pattern and in that circular
循环模式是这样的：
pattern it can basically be pooped out
它可以通过粪便排出体外，也
or it can enter back into the system and
可以重新进入体内。
the gut microbes are the The Gatekeepers
肠道微生物就像是“守门人”，
ah so they have the ability to actually
它们能够
control estrogen levels in the body on a
在一定程度上控制体内的雌激素水平。
certain level this is the reason why if
这就是为什么如果
you look at estrogen driven conditions
你观察雌激素驱动的疾病，比如
breast cancer breast cancer uh ovarian
乳腺癌、卵巢
cancer endometrial cancer
癌、子宫内膜癌和子宫内膜
endometriosis what you discover is that
异位症，你会发现
in these conditions there's damage to
这些疾病都伴有
the gut microbiome in all
肠道微生物组的损伤。
cases so and there it provides the
这
suggestion not yet proven it provides
提示我们，虽然尚未证实，但
microbiome may be
肠道微生物组的损伤可能正在
fueling um uh alteration of the estrogen
导致雌激素水平的改变。同样的情况
levels all right the same is also true
也适用
with uh testosterone or androgens male
于…… 睾酮或雄激素是男性
sex hormones which by the way of course
性激素，当然，
all men have estrogen and all women have
所有男性体内都有雌激素，所有女性体内也都有
male sex hormones as well it goes both
雄激素，这是
ways it's just the dominance between the
双向的，只是
two genders so there's a bacteria called
两性之间的激素比例不同。有一种叫做
cinium synin that's been known to
辛氏菌（Cinium synin）的细菌，已知会
basically affect male testosterone
影响男性睾酮
levels um so and there are conditions
水平。
for example polycystic ovary syndrome in
例如，女性多囊卵巢综合征（PCOS）就与
imbalance between the estrogen and the
雌激素和
androgens that's strongly associated
雄激素之间的失衡密切相关。
polycystic ovy syndrome and we suspect
我们怀疑
that the gut is Central to this okay so
肠道在其中起着核心作用。
first of all hormon the first point is
首先，
that hormonal related issues are
激素相关的问题
connected back to our gut microbes all
与我们的肠道微生物群有关。性欲、性
right so libido sex like these things
生活等等
obviously have a hormonal element to
显然都与激素有关，
them and this is the reason why erectile
这也是为什么勃起功能
dysfunction or uh I'm quite sure not as
障碍（或者说，女性性欲，虽然我不太确定
well studied because it's not as easy to
它是否像男性性欲那样容易被诊断出来，因此研究还不够深入）
would also be associated with the gut
也与肠道
microbiome I'm quite I'm almost positive
微生物群有关的原因。 我几乎可以肯定，我反复思考的这个
of this the question that I come back to
问题
that I find to be very interesting is
非常有趣，那就是
microbes play in
微生物在
between two human beings making me
两个人之间的“配对”中扮演着怎样的角色？它们是否真的能让我被
attracted to another human yes so and I
另一个人吸引？是的，所以，我又
come back to basic questions so now look
回到了最基本的问题。
I've been married for 10 years um so
我已经结婚十年了，所以单身
it's been a long time since I've been a
很久了。
single guy but I but I think we can all
但我相信我们都能
relate to you've been on a date and
感同身受，你肯定有过这样的经历：约会时，对方身上有某些东西——不是性格，而是其他方面，也许
there was something not not personality
是某种气味，让
perhaps the smell that you noticed that
你觉得“这太让人
turnoff this is not going to work right
倒胃口了，肯定不行”，
or it could be in the way that a person
或者可能是
kisses and these comp ability issues I
接吻的方式等等。我
am convinced actually come back come
确信，这些匹配度方面的问题实际上都源于
from the gut microbiome that they are in
肠道微生物群。它们在
a way matchmakers and that we're looking
某种程度上扮演着“配对者”的角色，帮助我们寻找
for good partners I can't put my finger
合适的伴侣。我无法确切地解释“合适的伴侣”
on exactly what that means what makes a
究竟是什么，什么构成了一段
good
美好的关系，
partnership but we do know that that
但我们确实知道，
partnership we discussed earlier
我们之前讨论过的这种关系
ultimately has an effect on your gut
最终会影响你的肠道
microbiome because you're going to
微生物群，因为你会与它们
share I I am convinced that sexual
共享某些东西。我确信 性
attraction is brought back to these
吸引力与这些
things and in animal studies it's harder
因素有关，在动物研究中，这
to do in humans but in animal studies
在人类身上更难实现，但动物研究
they have actually discovered that the
确实发现，
pheromone level s how you smell your
信息素水平（也就是你的气味）与
hormone is connected back to the gut
肠道
microbes so kissing is connected to the
微生物有关，接吻与肠道微生物有关，
gut microbes pheromones are connected to
信息素与肠道微生物有关，
the gut microbes sexual desire and
性欲、
libido and uh male erection are
性冲动和男性勃起也
connected to the gut microbes um I don't
与肠道微生物有关。我不
know where the line exists where it
知道界限在哪里，它们之间会如何
would stop I think it's all connected
划分，我认为它们都是相互关联的。
okay so if I want to be more attractive
所以，如果我想更有吸引力，
do I just need to eat some Sprouts what
我只需要吃些豆芽吗？
are you saying here because is it about
你在这里想表达什么？因为这关乎
compatibility or is it about got
兼容性还是
health I think that it's very clear so
健康？我认为这一点很清楚。
um attraction is a complex thing of
吸引力当然是一个复杂的东西，
course yeah we all have a different take
我们每个人的看法都不同。
you know I mean I have friends who
我的意思是，我有些朋友觉得
there's someone that they find
某个人很有
attractive and it's completely different
吸引力，而我的看法则完全不同。
that's good like I'm glad that we have a
这很好，我很高兴我们有
different take because variety is
不同的看法，因为多样性
necessary in terms of the genetic pool
对于基因来说是必要的。
right like we need everyone different
就像我们需要每个人一样，不同的
people to want different things that
人想要不同的东西。
being said
话虽如此，
I I I kind of feel
我感觉
qualities in a person that we would
一个人身上有一些与生俱来的特质，我们
universally agree are attractive MH and
普遍认为这些特质很有吸引力，而且
those tend to be measures of Health we
这些特质往往是健康的衡量标准。我们
usually think yeah you're right yeah
通常认为，是的，你说得对，是的，
yeah because I was going to say we think
因为我本来想说，我们把
of them as physical things right um
它们看作是外在的东西，对吧？
typically or things we can consume with
通常是我们用眼睛能看到的东西，或者我们用
maybe our ears you know jokes or humor
耳朵能听到的东西，比如笑话、幽默、机智、
or wit or personality whatever but it's
个性等等。但是，
it's completely plausible that there is
完全有可能存在一些
invisible things well I don't think that
看不见的东西。我不认为
the visible things can be disconnected
看得见的东西可以和
from the invisible things and that's one
看不见的东西分开，这也是
of the messages from the show today is
今天节目想要传达的信息之一：
that even the way that you look the
即使是你的外表，
radiance of your skin um your youthful
你皮肤的光泽，你年轻的容貌，
appearance um your uh your body shape
你的体型，有
and there's many forms of body shapes
很多种体型
that are attractive I mean I'm not um
都很有吸引力，我的意思是，我不是
saying that there's only one but the uh
说只有一种，但
these are manifestations of what's
这些都是内在状态的体现。
happening on the inside would you
你会
recommend supplements I know you've uh
推荐补充剂吗？我知道你已经……
you've produced your own supplement
你已经…… 我这里有我自己的补充剂，就在
drinking as we've been talking um called
我们说话的时候我一直在喝，它叫
38 Tera is it 38 Tera and 38 Tera what
38 Tera，是38 Tera和38 Tera吗？38 Tera的
that means is 38 trillion so this is in
意思是38万亿，
reference to the 38 trillion microbes
指的是
that live inside of us and this
我们体内生活的38万亿个微生物。这款
particular product is called daily
产品叫做每日
microbiome nutrition so in this product
微生物组营养，
we are using specific ingredients at
它使用特定的成分和剂量，这些成分和
specific dos that have been clinically
剂量都经过临床
proven to have an effect and to have a
验证，能够有效改善
benefit for your body that includes
身体健康，包括
things like improving your gut
改善肠道
microbiome it also means improving your
菌群，也就是改善排便。
bowel movements we talked about going
我们之前提到过，
from a Bristol one or two or a Bristol 6
从布里斯托尔1或2级，或者布里斯托尔6级
or S back to a Bristol 4 that's what I'm
或5级，恢复到布里斯托尔4级，这就是我
talking about right now but also
现在说的。
reducing digestive symptoms um so these
此外，它还能减轻消化系统症状。这些都是
regular use of a preotic it's easy it's
定期服用这款产品的好处。它很容易服用，是
a powder you've been drinking it I think
粉末状的。你刚才喝的，我觉得
it tastes pretty good I don't know what
味道还不错。不知道
you think oh was shocked Y and it was so
你觉得怎么样？哦，我当时很惊讶。是的，味道很棒，很
delicious yeah refreshing I've actually
清爽。我已经喝完了，
finished it all I had it started the
我之前喝了一点。
interview with it in this bottle here
采访内容就在这个瓶子里，现在都
and it's all gone where does where do
卖光了。
people find this 38 Tera 38 Tera is
人们在哪里能找到这款38 Tera呢？38 Tera可以
available at our website so you come to
在我们的网站上购买，网址是38
t.com and um and we are launching in mid
Tera.com。我们
January for the first time we're
将在1月中旬首次
launching in the US and Australia so in
在美国和澳大利亚上市，所以在
the UK it may be more difficult to get
英国可能比较难买到。
access to but just uh be aware that if
但是请注意，如果
there's enough of a demand then we would
需求足够大，我们会
serve that demand but if I if I am in
满足需求。如果我在
the UK I can still order it there would
英国，我仍然可以订购，只是可能需要支付运费之类的
the shipping cost okay super interesting
费用。运费……好吧，太有趣了！
I've learned so much today and it's
我今天学到了很多，这太
crazy because I didn't think I had much
不可思议了，因为我以为
else to learn about the gut microbiome I
关于肠道微生物群的知识已经足够多了，虽然我和
had lots of conversations about it but
很多人讨论过，但这次的采访真的
it's really it's inspired me it's
启发了我，让
informed me and it's given me a sort of
我了解了很多，也给了我一个切实可行的行动
actionable blueprint to start taking
方案，让我开始
action in my life and if I were just to
在生活中采取行动。最后，我想给
takeaway messages for everyone eat a
大家的建议是：多吃
wide variety of plants mhm fruits
各种各样的植物，水果、
vegetables whole grains seeds nuts
蔬菜，以及所有食物。 谷物、种子、坚果、
legumes every single one of these counts
豆类，每一种都算数，
coffee counts great absolutely so add
咖啡也算，当然，所以要让
more variety to your diet um add
你的饮食更加多样化，比如多吃些
fermented food to your diet get outside
发酵食品，多到户外
and exercise get a good night's rest hug
运动，睡个好觉，拥抱
that person that you care about focus on
你关心的人，专注于
human connection like these to me are
人与人之间的联结。对我来说，这些才是
where the priorities are at many of
最重要的。
these things by the way are completely
顺便说一句，很多这些事情都是完全
free we have a closing tradition on this
免费的。我们这个播客有个结尾的传统，
podcast where the last guest leaves a
最后一位嘉宾会留下一个
question knowing who they're going to be
问题，他知道这个问题是留给谁的。
been left for you when have you been
留给你的问题是：你
happiest in your life you may Define
一生中最快乐的时刻是什么时候？你可以用
happy in any way you like happiness is
任何你喜欢的方式来定义快乐。
uh I think what really matters and we uh
我认为快乐是真正重要的。
I think we have a problem in today's
我们当今
world of excessively fixating on the
世界的问题在于过度关注
objective things like like f money and
客观的东西，比如金钱，而
losing track of the things that are less
忽略了那些难以
measurable I have no clue how happy you
衡量的东西。我不知道你
are at home I have no clue right I have
在家里有多快乐，我真的不知道。我知道
an idea a of where you're at
你的
financially yet this is where um the
经济状况，但这才是
essence of life is and to me my my
生活的本质所在。对我来说，我的
happiness comes from my family it's the
快乐来自我的家人，这是我身上
side of me that you wouldn't know unless
你不会看到的一面。 除非
you like literally were my friend in
你真的在
Charleston South Carolina and spending
南卡罗来纳州查尔斯顿和我做过朋友，和
time with me the real person right but
我相处过，了解真实的我，否则你不会知道。但是，
um regardless of what you see on this
无论你在
camera or here on this episode um we are
镜头前或这集节目里看到什么，我们都是有血有肉、过着
real people with real lives and to me my
真实生活的人。对我来说，我的
happiness comes from the pursuit of
幸福来自于
things with my family um doing
和家人一起追求梦想，尽
everything within my power to fight for
我所能为
them and also just to enjoy time with
他们争取权益，也享受和他们在一起的时光，这就是幸福的意义所在。这是一个
about that's a beautiful answer thank
很棒的回答，
you so much Dr will you um you have a
非常感谢你，威尔博士。你拥有
remarkable ability to communicate but
非凡的沟通能力。 您不仅能清晰表达，而且在
we're talking about today and it's
今天我们讨论的这些问题上，您拥有无与伦比的丰富知识，这真的非常了不起。
really really incredible you're really
您真的非常
really incredible and you're doing so
了不起，您
much fantastic work for so many people
为这么多人做了这么多了不起的工作，
because it wasn't until a couple of
因为直到
years ago that I learned about the gut
几年前我才了解到肠道
and microbiome and I know because I can
和微生物组。我知道这一点，因为我
see the data that it that the society at
看到数据表明，
large are on a journey of now
整个社会正在逐步加深对
understanding the gut more and more and
肠道的了解，
the research that's coming out every
每年发布的研究成果都在
year is pushing us closer to that
推动我们更接近这种
understanding and that understanding
了解。这种了解
will unlock the things that we're all
将开启我们所有人
aiming for in our lives which culminate
生活中追求的目标，最终正如
in what you said there which is
您刚才所说，就是
happiness so that's the work you're
幸福。所以，这就是您正在
doing you're increasing public happiness
做的工作——提升公众的幸福感。
and I think that's um that's something
我认为这是
that's an incredibly worthy Mission so I
一项极其有价值的使命。因此，我代表
people that are listening today that got
今天所有收听到
to this part in the conversation and
这段对话，并且
that don't have a a means of reaching
无法
you directly thank you on behalf of all
直接联系到您的听众，感谢您。
of us thank you it's uh I'm honored to
我非常荣幸。
come on the show with you and for people
来参加我的节目吧！对于那些
who want to continue that conversation
想继续探讨这个话题的人，
this is why I put things out into the
这就是我把这些内容分享给大家的原因。
world and you can find me on social
你可以在社交
media as the gut health MD Instagram
媒体上找到我，我的账号是Instagram和Facebook上的“肠道健康医生”（Gut Health MD）。
Facebook I am on Tik Tok but I think a
我也有TikTok账号，不过好像被一个
14-year-old sto my handle so the g
14岁的孩子盗用了，所以
health mdore is how you'll find me there
你在那里能找到我的账号是“肠道健康医生”（Gut Health MD）。
but also you can come to my website the
你也可以访问我的网站
plant-fed got.com sign up for my free
theplant-fedgot.com，注册我的免费
email newsletter that's where how I
邮件订阅。
communicate like I think the most of
我觉得这是我最
effectively like I break down studies
有效的沟通方式，因为我会在那里解读研究成果。
there so come sign up for my email
所以快来注册我的邮件订阅吧！
newsletter and if you want to check out
如果你想
38 Tera you can learn more there as well
了解更多38 Tera的信息，也可以去那里看看。
notes I'm also going to put in the show
我会把所有内容都放在节目
notes which is the first time I've ever
笔记里。
done this I'm going to put the brief for
我还会把
this conversation in the show notes and
这次对话的概要也放在节目笔记里，这可是我第一次这么做。
what the brief is it's essentially all
概要的内容基本上就是
of the research my team did and they
我的团队所做的所有研究，他们把研究成果
condense it down into about 10 pages and
浓缩成了大约10页。
I think that's really important because
我觉得这非常重要，因为
we've covered so much ground here today
我们今天讨论的内容非常多，
that someone just listening someone who
所以…… 我只是在听，有人可能正在使用
have was having like a second screen
第二屏幕，
experience or was doing the dishes or on
或者在洗碗、坐
the tube or whatever there's a lot there
地铁等等，这其中有很多值得思考的地方。
the 10 pages you'll find in the show
节目笔记里有10页内容，
notes summarize this conversation the
总结了这次对话的
key takeways and the actionable insights
关键要点和可操作的见解。
and this is something I'm actually going
我打算以后持续这样
to start doing on an ongoing basis um
做。另外，
also the materials we discussed in this
我们在这次对话中讨论的材料，
conversation like the Bristol stall
比如布里斯托尔停滞
chart and all the other information that
图，以及你提到的所有其他信息（我会在
you after this conversation will be in
对话结束后收集这些信息），都会放在
the show notes including uh links to
节目笔记里，包括威尔
find Dr will everywhere on social media
博士在社交媒体
and on his website amazing that sounds
和他网站上的链接。太棒了，听起来
so cool can't wait to check that out
很酷，迫不及待想看看。
[Music]
[音乐]
as you guys know I'm a big fan of hu I'm
你们都知道，我是Hule的忠实粉丝，我是这家
an investor in the company and they
公司的投资人，他们
sponsor this podcast and what I've done
赞助了这个播客。我为
for you is I've put together for those
你们准备的是，我为那些
people especially that haven't yet tried
还没试过
hu but for all of those also that have
Hule的人，以及所有试过
but haven't tried my favorite products I
但还没试过我最喜欢的产品的人，
put together what I call the hule Steven
整理了一个叫做“Hule Steven
bundle which is a selection of my
套装”的东西，里面包含我
favorite products from hule including
最喜欢的Hule产品，包括
the Black Edition salted caramel flavor
黑版咸焦糖口味。 这款口味的蛋白棒
which is super high in protein and has
蛋白质含量超高，
17 servings per container the bundle
每罐有17份。套装里
also comes with their ready to drink
还包含他们家的即饮
product which is one of my all-time
产品，这是我一直以来最
favorite products from hu it is
喜欢的Hu产品之一。
convenient it is nutritionally complete
它方便快捷，营养全面，
and on those days when my life just gets
在我特别
very very busy it is my go-to product
忙碌的日子里，它是我的首选。套装里还有
you've got your hu bars which are
Hu能量棒，它们真的非常
absolutely gorgeous and in there you
漂亮。此外，套装里
also get this incredible t-shirt which
还有一件超赞的T恤，
is apparently according to lots of my
我的很多朋友都说这是
friends the best quality t-shirt they've
他们穿过的质量最好的T恤，
ever had and I don't really know why but
我也不知道为什么，但这件
there's something about this t-shirt
T恤确实
that's incredibly flattering this hu
很显身材。套装里还有一个Hu摇摇杯，
Shaker the link is in the description
链接
below in this podcast episode wherever
在下面的播客节目描述里。无论
you're listening to it there'll be a
你在哪里收听这期节目，都会有一个
Steven bundle link and check it
Steven套装的链接，记
out do you need a podcast to listen to
得去看看。你需要一个播客节目来听吗？
next we've discovered that people who
我们发现
liked this episode also tend to
喜欢这期节目的人往往也很
absolutely love another recent episode
喜欢
we've done so I've linked that episode
我们最近做的另一期节目，所以我把那期节目的链接放在
in the description below I know you'll
下面的描述里了，相信你会
enjoy
喜欢的。
[Music]
[音乐]